Climb, UK.
climb,uki.
you.
you.
Can you can provide
Can you can provide
how about you?
how about you?
find your treatment.
find your treatment.
this knowledge test
這個知識想驗
Then we invite people from this information office today
那我們今天請到這個資訊所的
around red garden
繞紅園
Distinguished Researcher
特聘研究員
explain to us
跟我們講解一下
he is
他在
The Second Decade of Academia Sinica
中研院的第二個十年
Multimedia Studies and Digital Archiving
多媒體研究跟數位典藏
then i want this
那我想這個
After I saw this topic
我看到這個題目以後
I said he must be ten years
我就說他一定十年
Almost ten years ago he gave
差不多十年前他有給過
a similar speech
一個類似的演講
I didn't have the honor of hearing his first speech
我沒有這個榮幸聽到他第一個演講
but i'm looking forward to this
不過我很期待這個
this
這個
we know this recently this
我們知道這個最近這個
this twenty or thirty years
這個二十年三十年
perhaps
大概
Anyone would think that saying this is
任何一個人都會覺得說這個是
knowledge explosion
知識爆炸這個
we use this
我們利用這個
media
媒體
Or use this power
或者是利用這個電數
benefit from this consultation
受惠的這個諮詢
then you can be anywhere
那你可以在任何一個地方
as long as you have internet
只要你有網路
You can probably find what you want to know
你大概都可以找到你想要知道的東西
So today we are looking forward to this talk
所以今天我們很期待這個演講
also hope
也是希望
Researcher Yaoyao especially wants to explain to us
那耀耀研究員特別要跟我們解釋
That is to say, it's not uncommon for you to find such advice.
就是說你找到這一些諮詢還不稀奇
Then he will ask for the old consultation that is no longer available
那他要把舊的已經沒有辦法得到的諮詢
fix it again
再修復過來
We commonly call it to explain the resurrection
我們俗稱就是解釋還魂
and this thing
還有這個本事
Whether it is this image
就是不管是這個影像
or video
或者是視訊
see him later
待會兒可以看到他
then let me make a brief introduction
那我先做一個簡單的介紹
Dr. Naruo is his student
那若博士是他的學
He is powerless Tsinghua University
他是無力清華大學
1981 Physics Series
1981年物理系列的
Then 90 years at Northwestern University
然後90年在西北大學
Northwestern University received a Ph.D. from the Department of Electrical Engineering
美國西北大學拿到電機系的博士
Then come back in 91
那隨後91年就回來
Come to our hospital to serve
到本院來服務
So it is probably the same from 1991 to now
所以91年到現在大概也是
20 years
20幾年
that's in the middle
那在這個中間
He also served as the Deputy Director of the Information Office
他也擔任過資訊所的副所長
And also our India Branch
還有也是我們印科
It is now called Indo Center
現在叫做印科中心
Formerly known as the Institute of Indian Technology and Engineering
之前叫做印科及工程研究所
Acting Director of the Preparatory Office
籌備處的代主任
Also worked as the director of the computer center
也做過計算機中心主任
In addition to being in this hospital, he is currently
那他目前除了在本院
In addition to the special researcher of the Information Office of the Institute
本院資訊所的特畢研究員之外
He is also in the Engineering Department of Jiaotong University
他也在交大資工系
Chengda Electrical Engineering Department
成大電機系
Professor of Peace
還有資工系和平教授
Also from Chung Yuan University
也是中原大學的
be a professor
前面講做教授
Of course, in China for more than 20 years
當然在國內20幾年
numerous awards
得獎無數
all important awards
所有重要的獎項
he got it all
他都得過
Young Assistant Award from the Central Hospital
從中央就院年輕助作獎
this one is for young people
這個是給年輕人的
Speaking of young people
以年輕人來講說
This is the highest honor in the country
這個是國內最高的榮譽
National Science Council Distinguished Award
國科會的傑出獎
three times
三次
Then National Invention and Creation Award
然後國家發明創作獎
There is also the rooting plan of the Central Academy of Fine Arts
還有中央優院的生根計畫
This is our Central Academy
這個是我們中央優院
forward-looking rooting
有所謂前瞻生根
with the theme plan
跟主題計畫
these are encouragements
這些都是鼓勵
someone who does research well
做研究做得很好的人
Internationally
在國際上
he too
他也得過
unmoving fellow
不移的fellow
in service work
在服務工作上
he also does a lot
他也做很多
Domestic and international conferences
國內的國際會議
He also made many arrangements and agreements
他也籌辦跟協議辦的很多很多
I think I won't waste any time today
我想我今天就不耽誤時間
then we are very much looking forward to hearing
那我們非常期待來聽
We want a special fellow to give us a great talk
要特別研究員給我們精采演講
The editor-in-chief thank you, Dean Wang, for the introduction
那個總編謝謝王院長介紹
last time i said
我上次講
In fact, it is about February 22, 2006
其實是講2006年的2月22
That's the private flight 222
那就是那個私自的班機222
I was going to say 10 years
我本來是想說10年
Because I was also working on the agreement article before
因為我之前也在做到協定文章
Say I hope 10 years from now
說我希望10年以後
Because of the research we comprehend
因為我們領悟的研究
You have been working for 10 years and can only speak for an hour and a half
你剛才做10年只能講一個半小時
because I can't speak math
因為不能講數學
can't talk about everything else
不能講其他的所有東西
So not only can I edit that picture for you to see
所以不只能修那圖片給你們看
So the 10-year thing will be about an hour and a half
所以10年的東西大概講一個半小時
If you retire in 2024
在2024年如果退休的時候
probably my whole life research
大概我終身的一輩子的研究
Can speak for four and a half hours
可以講四個半小時
I did the math
我算過了
four and a half hours
四個半小時
wait a minute listen
等一下你們聽聽看
why can only talk for an hour and a half
為什麼只能講一個半小時
then let me talk briefly
那我先簡單的講一下
Today I talk about this topic
今天我講這個題目
I suggest the second decade
我建議是第二個十年
The second decade is there for a reason
第二個十年是有原因的
I am in 1998
我是1998年
At that time, there was a plan to start digital singing
那時候有開始做數位典唱的計畫
That's a national industry
那這是一個國家行業
it hadn't started yet
那時候還沒開始
At that time it was a pilot project
那時候是一個前導型的計畫
Maybe it's a little simpler like me
可能像我也稍微簡單的講過去
Then I want to talk about this topic and the Internet
那我想講這個題目跟那個網際網路
is related
是有關係的
Internet circa 1993
網際網路大概在1993年左右
At that time began to be developed
那時候開始被發展出來
So in 1995 and 1996
那所以在1995、96那個時候
I felt at that time that for us
我那時候就覺得對我們來講
For people of our time
對我們那個時代人來講
was a big shock
是一個很大的震撼
That is to say, when I was studying, I was 19...
就是說我在念書的時候是19...
University is 1970
大學是1970
Graduated in 1980 and 1981
80年81年畢業
That 83 823
那83年823
When I went to study in the United States in 1983
83年去美國念書的時候
When I went to Wang Kruyman
那時候去Wang Kruyman的時候
In fact, Batch is still used in many cases
其實很多時候還是用Batch
It's the one that stacks the box with dirt
就是用污疊那個一盒的那個
level
層次
Then the main fear
然後主要很怕
They're all going to be messed up
他們都還會中心亂
sometimes get it wrong
有時候會弄錯了
will do it again
還會重新弄
So we were not the same back then
所以那個時候我們是不太一樣的
Well, the Internet was actually in 1993
那其實網際網路在1993年
Since then it has flourished
那時候開始蓬勃發展以來
that 1996
那1996年
In 1996
1996年的時候
we can use the Internet
我們就可以透過網際網路
to the floating museum in france
到法國的游浮宮
to see their painting
去看他們的那個畫作
It's a digital painting
就是數位畫的畫作
can go to browse
可以去瀏覽
At that time, for people of our generation
那時候對我們那一代的人來講
People who have always been the information
一直那資訊的人來講
was a big shock
是一個很大的震撼
more shocking things
更震撼的事情
actually another thing
其實是在另外一件事情
that is
就是說
At that time, we in the East actually did not
那時候我們東方其實沒有
make good use of the internet
好好的應用這個網際網路
So in fact culture
所以事實上文化
In terms of culture
從文化面來講的話
is a hassle
是一個麻煩的事情
why
為什麼呢
Because we all only look at western culture
因為我們都只看西方的文化
But our oriental things
但是我們東方的東西
we didn't build it
我們沒有建置起來
no words for him to type
沒有把他輸入的話
so then
所以那時候就
i'm guessing
我在猜
If we hadn't started doing it then
如果那時候我們沒有開始做的話
20 years later we are all
20年後我們整個都
In fact, culture is taken away by metaphors signed by the West
其實文化是被西方籤的比喻走
because they have cultural connotations
因為他們有文化的內涵
They can come and affect our whole youth
他們可以來影響我們這個整個年輕人
these new generations
這些新的世代
like japanese manga
就像日本的漫畫
affecting our children
影響到我們現在的孩子
has a deep influence
是有很深的影響
is the same reason
是一樣的道理
So starting in 1998
所以在1998年開始就
In Taiwan, we started to do some Internet
台灣我們就開始做了一些網際網路
right
對
I just want to lose it
就是希望把它輸過的話
At that time there were several lead-type intensifications
那時候有幾個前導型的激化
good
好
back then in 1998
那時候在1998年
There are three Pilot Projects
就有三個Pilot Project
Pilot Project is pilot intensification
Pilot Project就是先導型激化
One is the International Digital Library Corporation Plan
一個是International Digital Library Corporation Plan
it was 2001
是2001年
The seventh year's mission project was in 1998
那第七年任務Project是1998年
But since 1998, it has been investing in
可是1998年就開始投入
At that time there was National Archive Digitalization Program
那時候還有National Archive Digitalization Program
make a pilot plan
那做一個先導型激化
if our career loses it
我們事業把它輸過的話
hope that these cultural connotations
希望把這些文化內涵
I hope that these cultural connotations will start
希望把這些文化內涵開始
on our inner east side
在我們的內部東方這邊
It's Taiwan that constructed some cultural connotations for him
是台灣這邊把他建構一些文化內涵的東西
Then there is a problem
那那個時候就產生一個問題
we took some money
我們拿了一些錢
That's finally one of them
那終於也是其中之一
National Taiwan University too
台大也是
At that time, a host said
那時候有主持人說
let's not happen technology now
我們現在先不要發生技術
We just have to let him go up
我們就只要讓他能夠上去
It's good to be able to use it
能夠用就好了
It's good to be able to see
能夠看就好了
that's not for me
那不對我來講
i can't do this
我不能夠這樣做
when i first started
我那時候一開始的時候
I feel like saying
我就覺得說
if you're going to do this with me
如果你要在我做這個事情
Then take my postdoc
然後帶我的博士後
or my PhD students
或者是我的博士班學生
Although you give me money
你雖然給我錢
But from the point of view of our field of information
但是從我們資訊的領域的觀點來講
If I want to do RMD
我如果要做RMD的時候
If I just do some service
我如果只是做一些service
do some digitalization
做一些digitalization
a sacrifice for my students
對我的學生是一個犧牲
the other side is unfair
對方是不公平的
Because our Chinese medicine hospital must have research
因為我們中醫院一定要有研究
there is a laboratory
那有實驗室
Then we're doing this
然後我們在做這件事情
If it is simply input
如果是只是單純的輸入化的話
very unfair to students
對學生是非常不公平
So we insisted
所以我們那時候就堅持說
I don't care what he says
我不管他講什麼
I'm doing research anyway
反正我就是做研究
It's okay if you can't do it
做不出來沒關係
Then we were in 2001
那後來我們在2001
There has been a first episode since 2002
2002年開始就有一個第一集的
called
叫做
Your permission to use the Digital Archive Program
你允許用Digital Archive Program
the MDAP
這個MDAP
That was from 2002 to 2006
那是從2002年到2006年
At that time, I was developing technology very quickly.
那時候我就很快都在發展技術
At that time including Kiwi Jiufu watermark
那時候包括基維久福水印
include this
包括這個
DESOLATED DETECTION
DESOLATED DETECTION
those i did some of that
那些我做了一些那個
The news bureau uses the automatic technology of the storyboard
新聞局用那個分鏡的自動技術
THAT DOES MATTA DATA
那是做MATTA DATA
did something at that time
那時候做了一些東西
Then in 2006
那到了2006年的時候
This is the RMD of NID
這個那是NID的RMD
No one wants to be an RMD host
大家都不想當RMD主持人
Because when the PI of RMD
因為當RMD的PI的話
it's tiring to report
要去報告很累
i can't take some money
我不能拿一些錢
research i like to do
我自己喜歡做的研究
As long as it's related to the plan
只要跟計畫相關就好了
that 2006
那2006年
that time
那時候那個
At that time, the host Jian Lifeng
那時候原來主持人簡立峰
Dr. Jane
簡博士
he later begged
他後來討去
Hired by Google as general manager
被Google挖去當總經理
That
那
at that time
那個那時候的
Mead Choi
支付所所長米德財
you know
你認識
Now President of Zhouding University
現在是周定大學校長
he lied to me
他就騙我說
not far
沒掉不遠
you are the director of the computing center
你是計算中心主任
your computing center
你們計算中心
There are more than a dozen people who take this
有十幾個人是領這個
plan money
計畫的錢
you act temporarily
你就暫時代理
I will be silly, because I didn't think too much, just say yes
我會傻傻的,因為沒想太多,就說好啊
Take it, take it and you won't be able to throw it away
接了,接了就甩不掉了
By the end of December 2012, I have been the P.I of RMD
到2012年的12月結束,我都當了RMD的P.I
At that time, in 2007, the second five-year intensification of the digital arena will begin
那時候在2007年會開始第二期的數位典場五年激化
But at that time the National Science Council would have a
但是那時候國科會有一件
On the contrary, it is said that there was a digital learning national program at the Central University at that time
反而有說那時候中央大學那裡有一個數位學習國家型計畫
It is very strange that you want to do rituals but not study
那你要做典場不做學習,那是很奇怪的事情
So the National Science Council insists that the two plans should be merged together
所以國科會堅持說兩個計畫要merge在一起
So in 2007, 2005 and 2008 to 2012, the name of the second phase was changed
所以在2007年的時候,2005年和2008年到2012年就第二期的名字改了
It is called Mational Taiwan Etonian Digital Archive Program
叫做Mational Taiwan Etonian Digital Archive Program
TLDAP for short
就簡稱TLDAP
Then I will still be the P.I of this RMD
那我還是當這個RMD的P.I
Invote at that time, many people, many people now
那時候的Invote,很多人,目前很多人
Let me tell you about this sharing of R&D
我跟各位講一下 R&D 的這個分享
It was the share I hosted
就是我當初主持的那個分享
The annual gold fee is 140 million
一年的金費是一億四千萬
When you get that much money your hands shake
當你拿到這麼多錢的時候你手會巴抖
especially when signing a contract
尤其每次在簽合約的時候
in fact when signing
事實上簽的時候
Sometimes I have to ask if I will be arrested and imprisoned.
有時候都要問一下會不會被抓去關
Of course this congress will put 100 million of it in it
當然這個國會會把它一億放在裡面
is to build a homework team for digital learning that year build a team
是建立作業團隊給數位學習那年建立一個團隊
In fact, only 30 to 40 million can be used to do R&D together
那其實只有三四千萬是可以大家一起在做 R&D
Of course there are a few eight to share
當然有幾個八個分享
The first share is that we can expand the content
第一個分享是我們可以擴充內容的
The second share is for R&D
第二個分享是做 R&D 的
The third sharing is digital, these platforms are platform
第三個分享就是數位這些平台就是 platform
make a union directory
做聯合目錄
This place is very important
這個地方蠻重要
There are many institutions involved
參與的機構非常多
have included the Ministry of Education
有包括教育部
Including National Taiwan University
包括台大
including history museum
包括歷史博物館
Gu Guangde College
包括顧光德學院
Including Central University
包括中央大學
including Tsinghua University
包括清華大學
Including National Taiwan University and Academia Sinica, etc. have participated
包括台灣大學還有中研院等等都有參與
Basically these people
那基本上這些人
These institutions are basically
這些機構基本上是屬於
provider of digital content
數位內容的提供者
The content provider
The content provider
In particular, there are a lot of sayings in Chinese and English
尤其中英有很多行雲所
The timekeeping station or various
那個計時所或者是各種不同的所
they have a lot of literature
他們有很多文獻
so what i'm gonna say
所以我要把它說說的話
It's basically a comment provider
它基本上是comment provider
then come again
然後再來是
We also have a total request for proposal
我們還有total request for proposal
for example
譬如說
quarter university has some
四分大學有一些
back then
四分大學那時候
music department has many
音樂系有很多
The great musicians of all ages in Taiwan
台灣歷代的很偉大的音樂家
For example, Jiang Wen and so on
譬如江溫也等等
they have some
他們有一些
There are some sound content and their manuscripts
有一些聲音的內容跟他們的手稿
so let's talk about it
所以要把它說說的話
it doesn't matter the sound or the music
那不管聲音或音樂
So the manuscript has a lot of content
所以手稿有很多很多的內容
but you all know
但是各位都知道
These things are actually
這些東西其實
It is rendered in domainty way
它是在domainty的方式呈現的
That is to say, its content has sound
也就是說它裡面的內容有聲音
with video
有影像
have text file
有文字檔
and video files
還有視訊檔
Video files are the most troublesome
視訊檔是最麻煩的
There are many issues involved
那這中間有牽涉到很多問題
For example, video has a very large amount of data
譬如說視訊它的資料量非常大
Because the video it's kind of like a cartoon
因為視訊它是有點像卡通影片
it wants to fragment your visual comrades
它要片段你的視覺戰友
so it stipulates
所以它規定
More than 24 cards are required, it will fool you with more than forty strategies
要24張以上,它騙過你的四十多戰略
So European specifications are different from US specifications.
所以歐洲的規格跟美國的規格是不一樣的
One is 25 sheets and the other is 30 sheets, one second
一個是25張一個30張,一秒鐘
When there are 25 or 30 images per second
一秒鐘要25張或30張的影像的時候
The data of four sheets is very large.
四張的資料這樣非常大
Then we knew that we were going to digitize a lot of old videos, old photos
那我們就知道,我們要去數位化很多老影片、老照片
Then these things will be digitized and put in the database
那這些東西要變成數位化以後放在資料庫裡面
To texture nearby is to spend a little labor
附近去紋理,就是花一點勞力
But what to do next
但是接下來要怎麼樣去攪取
The quick way, the self-styled way to find what you want
那快速的方法,自封的方法去找你要的東西
that self-proclaimed method
那自封的方法
We all know libraries, when we're looking for books
我們都知道圖書館,我們要去找書的話
You gotta know Bosser's name best, don't you?
你要知道Bosser的名字最好的,對不對
then what is its title
然後它的書名是什麼
So when you go to search, the book will be quickly available
所以去搜尋的時候,書都會很快可以搜尋得到
Then we will suggest a multimedia database
那接下來我們會建議一個多媒體的資料庫
Including movies, digital movies
包括電影、數位的電影
Including sound, including video, including old photos, digitization
包括聲音、包括影像、包括老照片、數位化
You have to search for these things, how to search
這些東西你要去搜尋,要怎麼搜尋
This question is what our RMD sharing said to do
這個問題就是我們RMD的分享說要做的事情
let's do a
我們先做一個
able to address these complex, say video
能夠對這些複雜的譬如說視訊
able to do compression
能夠做壓縮
Compression is a big problem, why?
壓縮是一個大問題,為什麼呢?
Because you use a lot of video now
因為你現在用了一大堆視訊
That's because it's huge, so we have to do compression
那因為它量很大,所以我們必須做壓縮
Now the more commonly used compression may be
那現在比較常用的壓縮可能就是
Previously MPEG MPEG 1 2
之前的是 MPEG MPEG 1 2
1 MPEG 1 VCD MPEG 2 VVD MPEG 4
1 MPEG 1 就是 VCD MPEG 2 VVD MPEG 4
Then change to H.264 next
然後接下來變 H.264
If I say I use a little standard
如果說我是用一點標準
But let me tell you that MPEG and H.264 are different specifications
但是我跟各位講一下 MPEG 跟 H.264 它是不一樣的規格
MPEG it uses DCT 4 8x8 block
MPEG 它是用 DCT 4 8x8 block
A block to lead me to code
一個 block 去引扣我去編碼
H.264 uses four-layer
H.264 它是用四層式的
So there's a lot of engineering in between
所以這中間有很多 engineering
If at the beginning, now I save it in MPEG
如果當初,現在我是用 MPEG 把它存起來的話
Compressed, I passed 20 years later
壓縮的話,我過了 20 年以後
After a few years it became H.264
過了幾年以後變成 H.264
That's the middle shift. How to shift?
那是中間的轉檔怎麼轉
this is all issue
這都是 issue
Both are research issues
都是 research 的 issue
Then it's how we go to fast
然後再來就是我們要怎麼樣去快速的
able to do with these large amounts of data
能夠對這些大量的資料做
Notes Search
註解 搜尋
These are some e-sion
這些都是一些e-sion
it's all we have to deal with
都是我們要去處理的
So I don't want to say
所以我也不願意就是說
just do it
只是去做
supplementary work
補聽的工作
because you have to get these things done
因為你必須要把這些東西做完
Only then can we compare with the world
才有辦法跟世界上來比
so this is
所以這是
At that time we insisted
那時候我們當初堅持說
must do research
一定要去做研究
a very important reason
一個很重要的原因
That's what we built again
那這是我們又是建出來的
a theme
一個主題
This is Poto
這是Poto
Then what I'm going to say next is
那接下來我要講的就是
The first topic is imaging pending
第一個題目就是imaging pending
imaging pending
imaging pending
This is called the creation number
這叫做創改數
image creation
就是影像創改數
That's because Liao Hongyuan
那因為說廖宏元
then a few digits long
那就數位點長
Do you want to change history?
你要創改歷史嗎
you want image creation
你要影像創改數
Do you want to remove Mao Zedong?
你要把毛澤東拿掉嗎
Or put Chiang Kai-shek in it
還是把蔣介石放進去
Anyway it is
反正就是
what do you want to change
你要創改什麼
It's not like that
其實不是這樣子的
The purpose of innovation is to
創改的目的就是
everyone knows
各位都知道
You Leonardo acted in a movie
你奧納多演過一部電影
called ghost certification
叫神鬼認證
Inside the certification of ghosts and ghosts
神鬼認證裡面
you Leonardo
你奧納多
He is a top player in the world
他是一個全世界一等一的高手
Innovation Check
創改支票
just change the check
就是改支票
He was later caught by the FBI
他後來被FBI抓到
that is also that him
那個也那個他
He was a Wuhan guest and an FBI agent
他當武漢客是FBI幹員
Later this Ninaide
後來這個尼奈多
later worked for the FBI
後來是為FBI工作
Because as long as you have a five-photo profile
因為只要你一張五照的資料
He knew at a glance whether this house would
他一看就知道這家會不會
this is fake
這個是假的
because he uses something
因為他就用什麼東西
you take your fake stuff
你拿你的假的東西
he will know
他就會知道
So in fact the highest master
所以其實最高的高手
He must learn how to steal
他一定要學會怎麼偷
He will know how to take pictures
他才會知道怎麼照
So we have to start with the string change number
所以我們要先從串改數開始
How to change the number of strings
串改數就是怎麼樣
Make string changes in a photo
在一張照片裡面去做串改
let me show you this photo
我給各位看一下這張照片
This picture is my student
這張照片是我的學生
It's a doctoral class at Jiaotong University
就是一個交大的博士班
is working now
現在已經在工作了
He went to Egypt in 2009
他那時候到2009年到埃及的
an international conference meeting
一個國際會議開會
They opened an art gallery to see this
他們到開了一個美術館去看這個
my student
我那個學生
He is a Boban student
他是博班學生
Students from SJTU
交大的博班學生
This is the beautiful professor of Qing University
這是清大的美女教授
Professor Xu Qiulin
許秋林教授
At that time, he took a picture from the side
那時候他是從側面照了一張照片
Then Teacher Xu will come back
那徐老師回來就
According to this one, wow this one is really correct
照著這一張 哇這張真正正
But the place where we take the high light is who is behind it?
但是我們照高的地方是後面是誰啊
This is Huang Zhonglin from Qingla Electrical Engineering Department
這個是清拉電機系的黃仲林
He just stood there looking bored
他剛好很無趣的站在那邊看
So he Xu Congming said over there
所以他就許聰明在那邊說
Then can you please get rid of him?
那你可不可以拜託一下把他那個除掉
I get rid of him
我給他除掉
Removing it is visually there is nothing there
除掉就是視覺上那裡看起來就是沒有
this is tampering
這就是篡改術
This is tampering
這是屬於篡改術
Last time Shao Guangzhao was the senior, former director Shao Guangzhao
上次少廣昭那個學長 前所長少廣昭
He took a photo for me
他拿了一張照片給我
He said whether to be as good as you
他說要不要照你那麼厲害
did you do this
你有沒有這樣
you have a photo
你有一張照片
there are four people on it
這上面有四個人
can you remove one of them
你能不能把其中一個人去掉
take the other three and bring them all closer together
把其他三個人把他們都靠近一點
Because he said because the photo was a journal guest
因為他說因為這張照片是一個期刊客座
Gest Editor has three of the four in it
Gest Editor四個裡面有三個在裡面
He expects them to just delete that footage with
他期望他們就用乾除那張素材
Take a picture in mainland
在大陸拍了一張照片
tell me to take one of them off
叫我把其中一個人拿掉
The other three can all be together
其他三個人都可以在一起
I'll take it back then
那我就拿回來了
Just follow my Post-art
就跟我的Post-art
they're doing that mic
他們在做那個MIC
He's the doctor who plays and plays
他是那個彈加弄彈博士
say hey come come
說欸來來來
you help him
你幫他弄一下
fix it
弄一下好了
Then he said teacher
結果他說老師
You tell him how you can call us like that
你跟他講你們怎麼可以這樣呼嚨我們呢
Those four people were all put on it.
那四個人都是放上去的
understood
了解嗎
that photo is fake
那一張照片是假的
right
對
just go to the newspaper
就去報紙
As a result, the mainland said
結果大陸的那邊就說
very powerful
很厲害厲害
Our Taiwanese children are good
我們台灣孩子不錯的
good
好
Then do such a photo to do
那做這樣的照片要做
when buying photos
買照片的時候
Usually the old photos he sends are yellower
通常老照片他會發比較黃色
So the first thing we have to deal with is brightness
所以我們第一要處理的是亮度的問題
so we have to find a way
所以我們要想辦法
Take yellow photos
把比較黃的照片
become like this
變成這個樣子
the wrinkled part of you
那你皺摺的部分
no way
就比較沒辦法
why would the photo
照片為什麼會
will change color or
會變色或者是
wrinkled
有皺摺
the reason is because we
原因是因為我們
Many times we used to be early
很多時候我們以前早期
It was taken with negatives
就是用用底片照的
100 or 400 exposures
就是100或400的曝光
Then there are 24 or 36 discs like that
然後有24張或36張那樣的盤
so take that glue dot
所以拿那個膠點
to wash out the photo
去洗出來的照片
put on ass face
放在抽屁臉
after a long time
那放久了以後
I'm blocking you, after a long time you can use the inch white tree to help me remove it
我擋住你了,放久了以後你可以用寸白樹幫我移掉
That, maybe, maybe, that after a long time
那那個,可能,可能,那個放久了以後
He will sometimes have a tree crushing him, he will have wrinkles
他就會有時候樹壓到他幹嘛,他就會有皺褶
My wrinkles will produce something like this, of course the color will change after a long time
我皺褶就會產生這樣的東西,要久了當然顏色會變
So how do we think of a way to bring him back to his color
所以我們要怎麼樣想辦法把他,把他那個顏色調回來
The second one removes his wrinkles and does it automatically
第二個把他的皺褶去掉,自動的去做
That's the archives office, back then we had a lot of these things in the archives office
那是檔案局,那時候我們檔案局有很多這樣的東西
We need to deal with some old photos, but we want to be lazy
我們需要處理一些老照片,但是我們又想偷懶
Because we don’t want to talk about the Archives Bureau, we will just say it, because at that time all the photos of the items here will be given to you, please help us get them
因為我們不想說檔案局就說,因為那時候這裡的物品照片都給你,請你幫我們弄
Our best approach is to ask people, because that is to say try to develop some albums
我們最好的方法是,質詢的人,因為就是說設法發展出一些album
Let people who can't even use computers can use it, but we are lazy
讓連不會使用電腦的人都能用,但是我們就偷懶
Then we have to be smart to be lazy, so we have to make some automatic tools for them to use
那我們要很聰明才能偷懶,所以我們必須要做一些自動的工具讓他們用
This technology was transferred to the International in November 2010
這個技術在2010年的11月記轉給國際
The National Archives, wait a minute, has a video doctored book.
國家檔案據等一下有一個視訊的篡改書
was calculated to the National Archives in December 2011
是在2011年的12月計算給國家檔案據
It took us a year and a half to make this interface
我們花了一年半的時間把這個介面做出來
let them use
讓他們用
ok, this is this part
好 那這個是這個部分
Then you will ask me what the hell is this doing?
那你會問我說這個到底在幹嘛
it's math math this
是數學數學這個
For parts of this photo we used someone else's stuff
這個照片的部分我們用別人的東西
because someone else has done it
因為別人已經做過了
Let me introduce the colored part first
那我先介紹一下彩色的部分
In fact, it was said that the photo was destroyed.
其實講述過這張照片是被破壞的
Like the white part is destroyed
像白色的部分是被破壞的
The part with the color on it is good
上面是顏色的部分是好的
These two maths are to tell you
這兩個數學是要告訴你們
that is
就是說
This is a called confidential data control
這是一個叫confidential data control
These two look complicated
這兩個看起來複雜
ignore them
不要理他們
what is he talking about
他到底在講什麼呢
that is
就是說
Photos from this nice side
從這個好的這邊的照片
We hope to use good data to slowly simulate here
我們希望用好的資料往這邊慢慢模擬
Use good to influence to guess
用好的來影響來猜說
What should be the bad place
不好的地方應該是什麼東西
diffusion
擴散
then here is a line
那這裡有一條線
Red Curve
紅色的Curve
it
它
In fact, using the block of this road
其實用這個公路的方塊
just along this line
就沿著這條線
This customer is not loyal
這個客也不忠心點言客
Where should the customer want this width?
客要這個寬寬要放在哪裡
start tinkering
開始修補
tell a story
講個故事
this is too difficult
這個太難了
i tell a story
我講個故事
I said why only 15 years
我就說為什麼15年只能
The reason why 10 years of things can only be talked about for a minute and a half
10年的東西只能講一個半分鐘的原因
because i tell stories
因為我都講故事
there is an old lady
有個老太太
he made taipei
他做了台北市
Then he was a little demented
然後他有一點失智
so he got lost one day
所以他有天走丟了
just run to the police station
就跑到警察局去
the police asked him
警察局問他說
old lady
老太太
What are the characteristics of your neighborhood?
你家附近有什麼特徵呢
I said
我說
What
什麼
You'll cops all fall off the fish
你會警察都從魚上摔下來
There are 3,000 restaurants in Taipei since Holy Communion
台北市有3000家聖餐以來的
He said
他說
there is one elsewhere
別的地方有一個
female wife
女老婆
My policeman stood up slowly and said
我警察慢慢站起來說
He said
他說
you will go far
你還會別的很遠
OK for you
對你來說OK
for you
對你來說
That's a pity for everyone
那這樣大家受到可惜
Because the whole of Taipei City
因為全台北市
There may only be 30 such combinations
這樣的組合可能只這樣30個
easy to find
要找就容易
but I shrink
但我就縮小了
how do i tell a story
那我怎麼講個故事
these two things
這兩個事
i tell this story
我講這個故事
i'll tell you
我就告訴你說
where do you start
你要從哪裡開始呢
Just find a place to do complicated
就找一個做複雜的地方
the most complicated place
最複雜的地方
The most informative place
資料最豐富的地方
when repairing here
往這邊修補的時候
It will generate the least error
它產生的錯誤會最小
That's because this kind of error is here once wrong
那因為這種錯誤在這裡一旦錯了
it goes somewhere else
它會傳到別的地方去
will affect other places
會影響到別的地方
So we want Aeropropagation
所以我們希望Aeropropagation
The less passing of this error the better
這個錯誤的傳遞越少越好
So let's find a
所以我們就找一個
The most informative place
資料最豐富的地方
So it has a Conditon Stain Delta
所以它有個Conditon Stain Delta
Together it becomes a Priority Tent
合起來就變成一個Priority Tent
it's easy
這簡單啦
that's what we're looking for
那這就是我們找的
Then we will deal with this photo
那這這張照片我們就處理
用Conditon Stain Delta
用Conditon Stain Delta
that's the whole thing
這就是整個這些東西
Then what
然後呢
we just surround
我們就圍著
Put it together and let this
合起來以後就讓這個
Miss and Mr. Archives
檔案局的小姐和先生
won't get better
不會變好的
These guys have a flower rope
這些人有一個花索
it judges where
它去判斷是哪些地方
need to be changed
是需要改的
What places do not need to be changed
哪些地方不需要改
just tick
就勾一勾
Tick ​​a tick
勾一勾
Then the fabricator will do it for you
那後製造工就幫你做好了
this is done
這是做好的
Of course there are still some disadvantages
當然還是有一些缺點
Because some things are still not done right
因為有些地方還是做得不正好
But compared to this one
不過比起這一張
This one is a lot of people
這一張是好多人
good
好
this is about that
這個是有關於那個
Sugui doll
蘇貴娃娃
So it's image tampering
所以就是影像篡改
I'm going to talk about video tampering next.
接下來我要講視訊篡改
The reason for video tampering is the same as just now
視訊篡改原因跟剛剛那一樣
The reason for video tampering is because
視訊篡改原因是因為
I have to tamper with it so I can fix it
我要會篡改我才有辦法修補
So let me talk about tampering first
所以我先講篡改
fix it later
等下再講修補
The tampering here is my postdoctoral fellow.
篡改這邊配合就是我那個博士後
do this topic with me
跟我一起做這個題目的
he is
他是
He's been working with me for a long time with a Ph.D.
他拿博士在我這邊工作很久
Because the school he was born in is more famous
因為他的學校出生的學校比較有名
So he suffered a lot
所以他吃了很多虧
but he did a good job of researching
但是他做研究做得很好
That's exactly what happened
那這個剛其實是這樣
that is
就是說
if we do video
我們要做視訊的話
what are you going to do
你偏偏要怎麼做呢
usually
通常是這樣
video i just said
視訊我剛剛講過
he's a visual strategy that will fool you in a second
他是一秒鐘他會騙過你的視覺戰略
So he is twenty-five per second
所以他是一秒鐘二十五張
or thirty sheets of speed
或三十張的速度
then in this situation
那在這種狀況下
I'll pick the first one
我先挑第一張
here is a dog
這裡有一條狗
I want to make this dog into this first picture
我想把這條狗成這第一張
brush it up with a brush
用一個刷子把它刷一下
Then the yarn that is surrounded on all sides
那這個旁邊四面幫幫的紗
will gather inside
就會往裡面聚集
It's just that Emmy sister is very kind
就是剛剛那個Emmy姐很偏偏樣
So find a way to trick your eyes
所以想辦法去騙過你的眼睛
Then you see things that don't seem to happen
那你看見好像沒發生的事情
Then it will be automatic from the beginning to the end of this piece
那這樣就從這張開尾後面就自動的
it will remove the head
它就會把頭去掉
Then this is probably like this
那這個到底大概這樣
There are only so small words like this broken place
像這個斷掉的地方只有這麼小的話
Let's just use a simple Pixel Inc. Coca-Cola Circle
我們其實用簡單的Pixel Inc. 可可樂圈就好
it's easy to do
很簡單就可以做
this photo is so beautiful
這種照片這麼漂亮
This girl is also pretty
這個女生也漂亮
Many boys have this problem
很多男生都有這樣的問題
I gave it to other girlfriends when I was young
年輕的時候交給別的女朋友
how would you describe this photo
那你想描述這張照片
But I don't want your wife to see this
但是呢又不想讓這個讓你太太看到
If you take it off
那你握掉的話
After holding it off, it will be a black piece
這裡握掉以後這裡就黑黑的一塊
it won't follow
它不會跟後面
It won't be dug out and there will be a view behind it
它不會去挖掉以後後面有景色
Will not
不會的
So we're going to use this method
所以我們要用這個方法
in all directions
就可以把四面八方
Use Patch for large blocks
大塊的用Patch
make it up
把它補過來
Then you four...
那你這四...
it doesn't have to be true
它不一定是真的
but you seem to think it's real
但是你似乎這樣看起來以為是真的
Especially video is better
尤其視訊更好做
Because of the video it has many
因為視訊它有很多張
It has a lot of consecutive pictures around the time
它時間左右有很多張連續的
so you can borrow another one
所以你可以去藉別的張的
other places
其他的地方
come fix it
來把它修補
So it's probably like this on the face
所以大概在戴面上就是這樣子
Then we'll just use this picture
那我們就用這張圖就好了
remove everything
把所有的東西都拿掉
Do brightness first
先做亮度處理
movement on the time axis
在時間軸上的運動
let's try to find it
我們去把它盡量找出來
If it's broken, I'll fix it
有破損的地方我就把它修補
Then after the time axis is processed,
然後時間軸處理完了以後
I deal with space
我就處理空間
Handle broken ones in each frame
處理每個frame裡面壞掉的
patch it up
把它修補起來
then we've done our job
那我們就完成了我們的工作
Then this is Motion
那這個就是Motion
Motion has two
Motion有兩種
One is Global Motion
一種是Global Motion
There are two kinds of the same as wet
跟濕濕有兩種一樣
Damp has a cold exchange
濕濕有一種感冒交流
a rhinitis exchange
一種鼻炎交流
I think it's advertised very, very sincerely
我覺得它的廣告非常非常的誠懇
Why?
為什麼?
Because I will know rhinitis to eat?
因為我會知道鼻炎要吃嗎?
There are two kinds of colds
感冒有兩種
one kind of communication
一種是什麼交流什麼的
because its ad is honest
因為它的廣告很誠懇
because I carry it all
因為我都背起來
so i get a cold
所以我都會感冒
So I bought wet to eat
所以我就買濕濕來吃
that usually makes sense
那通常道理
There are two kinds of sports
運動有兩種
There are two types of movement in a VD
在一個VD裡面的運動有兩種
One is Global Motion
一種是Global Motion
One is Low Commotion
一種是Low Commotion
Global Motion is Camera Inch
Global Motion是Cameral Inch的
when you are using the mirror
就是你在運鏡的時候
The whole inside is moving with the Keymark
整個裡面都是隨著Keymark會動
So it's a Global Motion
所以它是一個Global Motion
Local Motion is what's inside is moving
Local Motion是裡面的東西在動
We're going to sneak around something that moves inside.
我們要偷偷處理裡面會動的東西
Previously had to deal with Global Motion first
以前要先處理Global Motion
make it up later
把它補回來以後
Only to deal with Local Motion
才去處理Local Motion
this will be correct
這樣才會正確
ok , then it ' s
好,那再來就是
That's when we make up
我們要補的時候就是這樣
Because we have the advantage that
因為我們有優勢就是說
because it's on the timeline
因為它在時間軸上
it takes 30 frames per second
它每秒鐘要30張
So it can go back and forth to find
所以它可以去前後找
some lost some
一些失掉的一些
something that wasn't there before
一些原來沒有的東西
go back and forth to find
去前後去找
make it up
把它補上去
then again
那再來
if you can't find it
如果找不到的話
It has the advantage of saying
它有一個優勢就是說
It turns out that there is no other place available
原來其他地方也沒有可以用的
use it
把它來用
what about the end
那最後呢
is the show result
就是秀結果
this dog is innocent
這條狗很無辜
But it's been shown many times
不過秀了很多次了
this dog
這個狗
that dog
那條狗
That
那
take a closer look everyone
各位仔細看一下
did it really work
它有真的成功嗎
the dog is gone
狗不見了
Hey, you're still here
欸,你這還在
This is how the movie was shot
這鬼片就這樣拍了
Actually I told me you don't need to be afraid of ghosts
其實我跟我講說你不要害怕鬼
The ghost is actually what dad did
鬼其實都是爸爸幹的
wait a minute there are more ghosts
等一下還有更鬼
look here
你看這裡
This was seven or eighty years ago
這是七八十年前
when the national assembly is in session
國民大會開會的時候
4th Treat says
第四招待說
Because the lady wants to parry the reporter
因為夫人要給記者招架
So the National Assembly represents Mrs.
所以國民大會代表了太太
she just walked out
她就從裡面走出來
I was trying to be a little bit of a prank
我本來是想做個惡作劇一點
Because my wife is hard to read
因為我太太長得難讀點
I was thinking how could she put
我本來想把她怎麼可以擺
stuff it in take one out
塞到把一個裡面拿掉
my wife in her thirties
我太太三十年代
But I was afraid she would hit me later
但是我後來怕她打我
so take a look here
所以各位看一下這裡
There is a red line here
這裡有一條紅線
Let her go past here
過了這裡就讓她不見
This is an old photo
這是古時候的照片
here is the video
這是來影片
it was originally made of film
它是本來是用膠捲的
So let's plasticize it now
那我們現在把它塑化
Then one can do something like this
然後可以做這樣的事情
You have seen ghosts, right?
各位有看到有鬼影對不對
gone
不見了
right here
這裏就在
And it's another time-space gate
而且又是一個時空的門
In the past, I only saw shadows
過去也會只看到影子
then next
那接下來
We use a Person
我們用一個Person
Farmering of Person Lang
Person 郎面的Farmering
just look at it this way
這樣一看就
Once it's fixed, it's done.
一本來就修補就弄好了
it becomes clear
就變得很清楚
so think about it
所以各位想想看
Is it possible to wear white history
是不是可以穿白歷史
It is possible to wear white history
是可以穿白歷史的
It is not difficult to wear white history
穿白歷史不難
i can wear white
我可以穿白
I put the people inside
我把裡面的人
it all looks the same there
那裡看起來都一樣的
can take it off
可以把它拿掉
but our purpose
但是我們的目的
not wearing white history
不是在穿白歷史
It's fixing an old movie that's broken
是在修改壞掉的老影片
fix it next
接下來修一下
Here is Zeng Ying's old video
這邊曾瑩拿的老影片
just nine seconds
就九秒鐘
here will be white
這裡會白白的地方
because the film was placed underground
是因為膠捲放在地下
it's been a long time
是放久了
it's wet
它很潮濕
so it's long
所以它長沒
Then we use steel rods like that
那我們用鋼桿那樣的
tamper number in turn
篡改數反過來
Anyway, let's find a way to go
反正我們想辦法去
make it work
把它做出力
we can
我們就可以
Of course not but white is very beautiful
當然不是反而白很漂亮
but
但是
You can do better than the original repair
就可以做比原來的修復了
Compare
比較
is better than the original
就是比原來的
There are a lot more
還有很多
this time we compare
我們這次比
This is repair, it’s easy to say, it’s easy to say, we want to take this software directly to the National Party Bureau and tell those ladies and gentlemen that you can use this software to repair this thing, it’s impossible,
這個就是修復,這個講很容易,講很容易,我們想把這個軟體直接拿給國家黨院局跟那些小姐先生講說你們就用這個軟體去修復這個東西,不可能的事情,
So it took us a year and a half. It took Dr. Tan a year and a half. He made an interface. This was in 2012.
所以我們要花了一年半,這個坦博士花了一年半,他做了一個介面,這是在2012年紀團隊國家黨院局,
This video, this FRIENDS is to be repaired, the red part is to be painted with a brush, so this part is long, I want to brush it off,
這張影片,這一張FRIENDS是要修補的,這個紅色的部分就是用刷子把它刷一下,所以這個部分是被長的,我想把它刷掉以後,
The ten versions made by Dr. Tan, for example, the first version may use the previous timeline, and there are three previous versions.
這個坦博士做的十個版本,譬如說第一個版本可能是利用前面時間軸的,前面也要刷三張,
The second version is the last two, the third version is the first two,
第二個版本是後面的兩張,第三個版本是前面的兩張,
Two pictures in the back, two pictures in the back, so there are ten versions, different versions
後面兩張,後面兩張,這樣有十個版本,不同的版本
It takes different intervals to fix this one
它取不一樣的區間去修復這一個
Then these versions are its different versions
那這幾個版本就是它不同的版本
So this gentleman or lady who restores old videos
所以這位修復老影片的先生或小姐
She only needs to look at these ten versions and decide which one to look at
她只要看著這十個版本,看哪一個就好
These seven hook up, and then replace this one
這七勾起來,然後就取代這一張
In this way, we can do this automatically and automatically
這樣的話我們這個就可以自動的,辦自動的方法
But it is much more convenient than before
但是已經比以前方便很多
In the past you had to fix this thing, especially if you were on a photo table
以前你要修復這東西,尤其你在照相表
how does it fix this thing
它怎麼修復這個東西
Of course it will make you prettier
當然會把你變得漂亮一點
I really can't make you beautiful
我真的沒有辦法把你變漂亮
But at least some bad things can be put away
但是至少就可以把一些不好的地方
fix it as much as possible
把它盡量的修復
it's automatic
這是自動的
what was just said
那剛剛講到的是
Here I go, doing such a boring thing
我講到這裡,做了這麼無聊的東西
it can make a good push powder
它可以出很好的推粉
is that you just put your heart on it and put it above the science
就是你只要用心,把它放在科學上面
Heart to science, don't use borrowed material is bad
心向科學,不要用藉由的素材是很糟的
Because that thing is hard to push powder
因為那東西很難出推粉
But I just want to think of a good topic
但是我只要想一個好的題目
it's all above
就都是上面
can also be used in real applications
又可以做到真正的應用上
can really let go of anything
又可以真的放掉任何的
i would not sacrifice my students
我就不會犧牲我的學生
My students have a future
我的學生以後有前途
i can't sacrifice them
我不能夠犧牲他們
But I want to do such a bad topic
但是我要做這麼爛的題目
So I want a good science inside
所以我要想一個好的科學的裡面
What is Twitter doing here?
那這邊推特是做什麼呢
is done when there is an action
是做當有一個動作
Because what we've just talked about is background stuff.
因為我們剛剛講的都是背景的東西
It is easy to make up for the background
背景的東西要補很容易
because time goes by
因為時間走
That background doesn't move very well
那個背景那不太會動
But if foreground something
但是如果前景的東西
How do you move if you happen to be covered by the head of the sect?
剛好被這個掌門遮到的話怎麼動
Let's say I'm walking halfway
譬如說我在走路走到一半
something happened to be broken
剛好有地方壞掉
There is an action in the middle
中間有個動作
When six or seven cards are dropped
掉了六七張的時候
how do i fix it
我怎麼樣去修復
Human movement is a very complex movement
人的動作是一個非常複雜的動作
Because people are highly valued sports
因為人是高度的節值運動
that's worth it
那是節值的
It is articulated motion
就是articulated motion
it will move a lot of joints
它就會很多關節在動
You don't look like you move on you
你不像是你動動在你身上
just have a lot of joints
就是有很多關節
Then this problem is a very complicated sports problem
那它這個問題是一個很複雜的運動題
so when it's walking
所以當它在走路的時候
In fact, many places will move
其實很多地方都會動
So how do I use a very short
那我怎麼樣無論用很短的
very precise description
很精確的描述
then pinch him in
然後把他捏進去
that's a very difficult question
那是一個非常困難的問題
Let's take an example of the simplest
那我們去舉個例子最簡單的
He walked over from one of these two people
這兩個人他從一個從那邊走過來
this is my student
這就是我的學生
one came over there
一個從那邊走過來
one walks over there
一個從那邊走過去
There is a rendezvous in the middle
中間有交會
what about this guy
交會的這個人呢
can i take him off
我可不可以把他拿掉
let the one blocked
讓那一個被擋住的人
Walking from left to right without being blocked
從左邊走到右邊都沒有被擋住
can you
可不可以
That's the problem we're going to do
這就是我們要做的問題
It's a matter of tenure
就是一任的問題
that's what i just said
就是我剛剛講的
when blocked
當被擋住的時候
or a video somewhere
或者是一個影片在某些地方
Where it moves, he is
會動的地方他被
It's not long, it's not broken
沒長沒破壞了以後
How can I get him back to school?
我怎麼樣去把他學復回來
this problem
這個問題
The previous problem is easier
前面的問題比較容易
because of the background
因為背景
here is the foreground
這裡是前景
The prospect is more difficult
前景的地方比較難
good
好
Then of course we did a few moves
那我們當然做了幾個動作
The first is to say
第一個就是說
I put the complicated
我先把複雜的
my section
我的區段
simply use some projection
簡單的用一些投影
divide it
把它分割
Here are a few of the simplest things
這個這裡用幾個最簡單的東西
My boys and classmates
我這邊各位男生同學
Boy students speak
男生同學講
you have to listen to them
你們要聽他們講
you see
你們看
This place is just pissed off
這個地方簡直動氣了
The place where the least movement is projected is the navel
運動投影過來最少的地方就是肚臍
So if your belly button is big, watch out
所以你的肚臍如果肚子很大的話要注意一下
In fact, the amount of exercise is the smallest
就是其實運動量是最小的
Because we put the belly in different movements
因為我們把肚臟不同的運動
After projecting it over
把它投影過來以後
After Number 20, I found your place with the lowest amount of exercise
Number 20以後發現你這個運動量最低的地方
It's where the navel is
就是肚臍的地方
So we divide this person's body into the upper half and the lower half to describe
所以我們把這個人的身體分在上半部跟下半部去描述
Then we have to make a specific description
那我們要做一個具體的描述
We have a way to fix it, right?
我們才有辦法把它修補對不對
Then the method we use is to choose Context
那我們用的方法就是選Context
So it doesn't have to know
所以它不一定要知道
Anyway, it's just a description, right?
反正就是要描述對不對
But this one is more important
但是這個下面比較重要
Here's what you, a good doctor, should know
下面這你知好博士應該知道吧
You know your professor should be at
你知好你教授應該在
I dare not speak nonsense about the mathematics department
它這個數學系我不敢亂講
I know for sure it will come, but I dare not talk nonsense
我知道確定它來我又不敢亂講
That space conversion is like this
那那個空間轉換是這樣
That is to say we speak phonetically like this
就是說我們在語音上是這樣講
That is to say, I hope to say that in MISPACE
就是說我希望說在MISPACE裡面
If I want to describe the job
我如果要做工作的描述的話
It is very complicated to measure it differently for each person
每一個人不同量下去的很複雜
Can I convert it to a converted Space
我可不可以把它轉換到一個轉換的Space面去
Then his average rotation here and there has nothing to do with the size change
那他在這裡在那個地方旋轉平均跟大小變化都沒有關係
this problem
這個問題
So we have to make the original knowledge
那所以我們要做把這原來的那個知識
It turns out that I have done a lot of knowledge
原來做了很多知識
One knowledge moves its hope elsewhere
一個一個知識把它希望搬到別的地方去
Then this law is issued using an ISO-MAP
那這個頒法是用一個ISO-MAP
It is a method of induction and high learning that can be applied
它是一個能應應的感應學與高學的方法
that's how it works
它就做法是這樣
That is to say, I hope to move all the people in Taipei to Kaohsiung
就是說我希望把台北市的人全部搬到高雄
But there is a limitation and a conditional limitation that is
但是有一個限制有個條件的限制就是說
I hope people in Daan District are still in Kaohsiung or Daan District
我希望大安區的人還是在高雄還是在大安區
People in Daxiong District are still in Daxiong District
大雄區的人還是在大雄區
People in Wenshan District used to be able to get together in Kaohsiung
文山區的人過去高雄用還是就是能夠聚在一起
So the interior will put it out
所以內部會要把它擺出
In this case, through a so-called ISO-MAP method
那這樣的話就是透過一個所謂的ISO-MAP的一個方法
It's easier to explain with this picture
那用這個圖來解釋比較容易
Suppose I have a continuous action so many
假設說我有一個連續的動作這麼多張
In the space of this transform
在這個transform的space
I just talked about the maple space of the transform
剛剛講那個transform的Maple space
It's not as if going here to here is
它是不當做將這裡到這裡是
That track came this way, transported here
那條軌跡這樣過來,運到這裡
there is a red line
有個紅線
Let's say I'm short because of my age
假設說我因為長沒的關係
A few friends are broken here
這裡中間斷掉了幾個Friend
It's equivalent to saying that I'm broken after I got here
它相當於說我走到這裡以後斷掉了
and start again here
然後在這裡又開始
So how do I follow this path from this place
那我怎麼樣從這個地方沿著這個路徑
There are many points along the way
沿路中有很多點
I find a most appropriate trajectory
我找到一個最適當的軌跡
let it go here
讓它走到這裡
make it look
讓它看起來
after connecting
連起來以後
make it visually continuous
讓它視覺上看起來是連續的
this is what we do
這是我們要做的事情
the problem is this
這問題是這樣
then i just said
那我剛剛講過
Let's flip that Nebel all over
我們把那個Nebel全部翻過去
So Nebel is still Nebel
所以Nebel還是Nebel
When I arrived in Kaohsiung, it was still Nebel
到了高雄還是Nebel
So in this situation
所以在這種狀況之下
we ask to say
我們要求說
when we search step by step
我們一步一步地找的時候
the next person you're looking for
你找的下一個人
Must be your Nebel close by
一定要是你的Nebel很近
The second is the directionality when you look for it
第二個就是你找的時候那個方向性
Must be directional
方向性一定要
Can it change too much
要不能變化太大
Because it wants to say it can't change too much
因為它希望說它的變化不能太大
So we have these two constraints of doing
所以我們有做的這兩個限制
So we did some traditional
所以我們做了一些傳統的
Then do a BitWord prediction
然後再做一個BitWord prediction
Then we arrange a Priority list for each point of Ford Word and BitWord prediction
然後把Ford Word跟BitWord prediction 每一個點我們都是排一個Priority list
It is the definition name definition name definition name definition name each age point each has a definition name definition name definition name definition name definition name
就是定義名定義名定義名定義名 每一個年齡的點 每一個都有定義名定義名定義名定義名
So here's a story to tell, a story about my life.
那這裡要講個故事 講個人生的故事
Each defined name and the last set define the name
這個每一個定義名 最後一個集合就定義名
Obviously my kid knows it, obviously the kid takes the first place in the exam every month, he doesn’t necessarily define the name in the exam every day
明明我小孩子都知道 明明小孩子每個月考都考第一名 他每天考不一定定義名
So this means that there are a lot of people who are in the local area and they can comment on it.
所以這個意思就是說 有很多人他在local 他在評一下 他可以
But he has no exceptional majority, he has no greater vision, no one thinks
但是他沒有格外多數 他沒有比較大的視野 沒有一個思考
The general direction is relatively large, a thought of Wei Mou
那個大方向比較大的 微某的一個思考
So it's like he takes the first place in every exam but he only defines the name there
所以就像他每次考試都考第一名 但是他只有在那裡定義名
He will not define the name when he goes out, because some he dare not watch him do it as if he kicked a lot of things
他出去就不會定義名 因為有些他不敢看他做就好像踢了很多東西
Because of the things that come out of the test, how should the football style be blown?
因為考出來的東西足球風要怎麼吹
There are so many lectures in the textbook
裡面課本面那麼多講
So many times we learn
所以很多時候我們都學問
Actually
其實是
The book is messed up and I missed it
書本七八糟錯過來了
so in this place
所以在這個地方
we just use one
我們就用一個
Marco Manfio
Marco Manfio
what he does is
他做的就是
Blood Over Optimization
Blood Over Optimization
that is to say he
就是說他
not take everyone down
不是取每一個都低迷
He just takes something and puts it together
他就取什麼東西合起來
Will definitely in the future
以後一定
total downturn
全部的低迷
make you visually look
讓你視覺上看起來
is very free
是很免蓄的
very eye-catching
非常的動眼
that this one
那這一個
I will learn here
我這裡會學一下
this is my student
這是我的學生
It's the student who was just presenting
就是剛剛在向的那個學生
This is too big
這交大了
I found out he has graduated
我發現他已經畢業了
he works on his own
他自圓工作
Then here's his action
那這裡他的動作
what we are going to do here
那我們這裡要做的
Our interface is like this
我們介面是這樣
That is to say, what I just did
就是說我把他剛剛的動作
deduct
扣掉
from own
從自己的
get your share
分到自己的分
remove it all
都把它去掉
It's human animation
就是用人動畫
remove it
把它去掉
Then we use Forework
然後我們用Forework
Bitwell Tracking
Bitwell Tracking
Then Optimize
然後Optimize
find these things later
以後找到這些東西
I figured it out and plugged it in
我算出來以後塞進去
just hope he visually looks like
就希望他在視覺上看起來
Although the seven chapters are missing
雖然這七章不見了
but i go somewhere else
但是我去別的地方
unfolded
展開的
After it is inserted into the sip, your movements seem to be continuous
那它塞進去這個sip子以後,那你這動作看起來是連續的
Okay, maybe that's the case, then I'll fix it
好不好,大概是這樣,那我要修一下
Here is a road section, which often happens abroad
這裡有一個路段,這是國外常常發生的
This is when we lost the journal, that Evita said that you should try this benchmark
這是我們丟期刊的時候,那個Evita說你們要試試看這個benchmark
Can I compare myself with others
可不可以,我跟別人比
this is me again
這是我再過一次
it walks through this pillar
它走過這一個柱子
Then we have to do something like walking through this pillar without that pillar
那我們要做一個就是說好像走過這個柱子,沒有那個柱子一樣
Okay, let's take a look
好不好,那各位看一下
yes sorry
對,抱歉
right it is
對不對,它就是
We are all better than the best, I don't want to broadcast it now, then I will quip to see that there is a problem
我們都比那個最好的都好,我現在就不要播,那我quip看那有一個問題
Then this is another example, this is the example we originally gave, this is one of my students, I am looking for the fattest student
那這是另外一個例子,這是我們原來給的例子,這是我一個學生,我找一個最胖的學生
Because, why find the fattest student, because when it walks over there, the fattest student can cover the column
因為,為什麼要找一個最胖的學生,因為它從那邊走過去的時候,最胖的學生可以遮住這柱
Well, that's just that difficulty is the hardest
那,那只是那個難度是最難的
then we can take a look
那我們可以看一下
You see it's been covered for a long time, because it's so thin, it's been covered twice as long
你看它對遮了很久,因為它很瘦,它對遮了兩倍的時間
This is how we find a way to identify a crude object
這是我們想辦法再identify a crude object
This is the result we made, as if that didn't stand there either
這是我們做出來的結果,好像那個也沒有站在那裡面
So in fact, this problem can be solved
所以其實這個問題是可以解的
In the following part, you will feel even more that one day the current computing center will discuss Wang Dawei
接下來這個部分你就更覺得,有一天那個現在的計算中心主論王大維
Wang Dawei told me, you are so powerful, you are like this
王大維他就跟我說,你那麼厲害,你這樣
The two Chinese in front of the activity center, can you ask him to type
那個活動中心前面那兩個中文,你能不能叫他打起來
I said you are crazy, you bought it for 9 million, you don’t want to give it away
我說你瘋了,900萬買的,你不要送的啦
Because what if it breaks in the fight?
因為打起來萬一壞掉怎麼辦
But he gave me an idea, a good idea
但是他倒是給我一個idea,一個好的想法
That means can I just give me a picture and I'm going to apologize
就是說我能不能只給我一張照片,我就要道歉
Let me take another photo for you, I tell you to move, is that okay?
我幫你再一張照片,我叫你動起來,可以嗎?
It's ok, because that thought just now is ok
可以耶,因為剛剛那個想法就可以
so we can be like this
這樣我們就法是這樣
never talk
一直不要講了
That's it, this is the eight-star female president
就這樣這是八星的女總統
It's just that mother is miserable recently
就是最近那媽很慘
It's her eight stars who spent more than 10 billion
就是她八星用了100多億
Then Cosmopolitan
然後世界主義賽
then no first place
然後就沒有得第一名
so miserable
所以很慘
Then we only have one picture of her
那我們只有她的照片一張
i might be able to make her move
我可能可以讓她動
may be able to make her move
可能可以讓她動
Because this goes back to the question
因為這回到剛剛的問題
I made a mistake just now
剛剛我講錯一個問題
If I'm not wrong you correct me
你是否我沒有講錯你糾正我
Because the law should not be corrected
因為就法不要糾正
i'm actually talking
我實際上在講
that we are doing that
那個我們在做那個
I just talked about transform
transform的時候我剛剛講過
If I get to the mask of transform
我如果到transform的面具的話
Manual's Mask Words
Manual的面具的話
I can
我可以
rotation, translation, scaling, environment
rotation, translation, scaling, environment
Just stay the same
就是動不變
Then I can't call this president
那我不能夠叫這個總統
So show me these moves
所以這些動作給我看
what should I do
我怎麼辦
because the front side
在因為正面那邊
rotation, translation, scaling
rotation, translation, scaling
I just ask a student to do it
我叫一個學生做就好了
i am a student
我叫一個學生
and leave some tracks over there, right?
然後在那裡留一些軌跡在那邊對不對
So I can Normalize this picture
所以這張照片我就可以把它Normalize
Then switch to that Space to find its trajectory
然後轉換到那個Space去找它的軌跡
See which point the Match is at
看到Match到哪個點
Pull to both sides after Match arrives
Match到以後往兩邊拉
Then put StoeD's Match on it
然後再把StoeD的Match弄上去
this is done
這就做出來了
so it can stare
所以它就可以瞪了
Of course there is still a disadvantage
當然還是有一個缺點
I can't help it because of our sleeve
因為我們那個袖子我也沒辦法
some things are not so easy
有些東西沒有那麼容易
but it moves
但是它動
and you look up beyond this angle
而且你看往上超過這個角度
down beyond this angle
往下也超過這個角度
So you can move without words
所以無得話也可以動
Mao Zedong can also move
毛澤東也可以動
The dean can also move
院長也可以動
So the dean only has this photo
所以院長只有這張照片
And it's the picture we rotated from up
而且是我們從往上旋轉出來的照片
then be able to move it
那就能夠把它動
So research is actually quite fun.
所以其實研究是蠻好玩的
So it doesn't count too much if you don't limit yourself
所以說不限自己錢算的不多
Actually doing research is very interesting
其實做研究是非常有趣的
good
好
The next thing I want to talk about is Tangyou production
那接下來我要講的是湯游production
What is the relationship between this and the length of the digit point?
這跟數位點長的關係到底是什麼
When some old films were shot, it was
有些老影片拍到的時候就是
Because the previous camera was not good
因為以前的照片機不好
so the old one
所以以前的那個
It wasn't digital before
以前不是數位
digital now
現在是數位
It used to be that analog
以前都是那個analog
So when he was
所以在的時候他那個
Not well tuned without contrast
沒有contrast調的不好
It's because his contrast is not good.
說是他的對比調的不好的話
He actually has some places
他其實會有些地方
His performance will be very bad
他的呈現會非常的不好
so this
所以這個
Tangyou production means
湯游production的意思就是說
Automatically find the inside of the photo
自動的去找出照片裡面
That comparison is poor
那個對比比較差的
Where the contrast is relatively poor
contrast比較差的地方
Because usually the contrast is poor, which means
因為通常對比比較差的意思就是說
little change in his routine
他的規律的變化很小
so often
所以很頻繁
so you can't see the details in him
所以你看不出他裡面的細節
can not tell
看不出來
So our
所以我們這個
This classmate is Xiao Deyu
這個同學叫蕭德玉
I have written an article about cover-up
我有寫過一篇遮暴的文章
we are doing this research
我們在做這個研究
After the result was written, it was so touching
結果寫完以後寫得太感人了
A lot of girls who are always vegetarian ask me where she is
很多總大致素的小姐問我說她在哪裡
want to marry her
想要嫁給她
while she is excellent
趁她很優秀的
she's still in that seattle
她現在還在那個西雅圖
Watching the Seattle
Watching the Seattle
because i'm about to graduate
因為我已經快畢業了
I have graduated from National Taiwan University
我台大電子機已經畢業了
Then this is Thorough Production
那這個就是Thorough Production
This is the only one I can't see clearly
我竟然就這一張我本來看不清楚
After I passed Thorough Production
我經過Thorough Production以後
I can see this love quote on Saham
我就可以看到這個情語在Saham上
considering
在考慮
This was done earlier
這是比較早期做的
Made in 2008 and 2009
2008、2009那時候做的
good
好
The first step is to compare
那第一步做法就是我們先把對比
Find it in a lower place
比較低的地方找出來
Then what
然後呢
Make adgregation of these places that are relatively close
把這些地方比較接近的地方做adgregation
then again is to put it simply
那再來就是把它乾脆就
adgregation
adgregation
I will also compare it and enlarge it
我還會把它對比把它放大
For example, the rules here
比如說它中間這裡的規律
Originally only 10
本來只有10
I now increase it to 50
我現在把它加大變成50
Then it will be compared
那這樣它對比就出來
it's easier to see
就比較容易看清楚
But there is a difficulty with this rule
但是這個規律有個難的地方
That is to say, you put this
就是說你把這個
This is an area compared to
這是一個區域對比方到的
what about other places
別的地方怎麼辦
It's somewhere else
是別的地方是圖物的
So we handle the bounds with
所以我們用處理邊界
We use Biofeter
我們就用Biofeter
Biofeter's Fetter
Biofeter的Fetter
After processing it, it becomes like this
把它處理完就變這樣
really easy
講真的容易
but did it for a year
但是做了一年
been doing this for a long time
做了很久這樣
not so easy
不是那麼容易
So I just told you
所以我剛才跟各位講一下
decade east west
十年的東西
It's over in an hour and a half
一個半鐘後就講完了
this is what we made
這是我們做出來的
the result made at that time
那時候做出來的結果
there's a downside
這有個壞處
so we go out and take pictures
這樣我們出去照相亂照
because it doesn't matter anyway
因為反正無所謂
this is that
這個是那個
Model photo
型案的照片
grabbed from the internet
從網路上抓下來
This is real
這是真的
Look, this is Baojing
你看這是保鏡
Just use the agency to do this
就是拿機關這樣做
This is a posing picture, he thinks he is black enough, so he can see the camera, not necessarily like it
這是一個擺圖,他覺得自己夠黑,所以他就看得鏡頭,不一定喜歡這樣
It didn't turn out well, so he found out
結果就不太好,他就找出來
This is an old photo, because our target is actually an old photo, the old photo you want to do
這是老照片,因為我們其實我們的 target 是老照片,你要做的老照片
It is actually very difficult to make old photos, because the bottom of his table is dark
老照片其實很難做,因為他這個桌子底下都黑了
There are no cultural relics in the cake here, so as I said, there are cultural relics in the cake, and the efficiency of children is not as good.
這裡蛋糕也沒有文物,那麼像自己說,蛋糕也有文物,小孩子效能也有差那一點
You can also see things under the table, which is the old photo he improved, the quality of the old photo posted by Su Bai
桌子底下東西也看得到,就是他改善的這個老照片,蘇柏放的老照片的品質
The next one is what we are going to do, it is also in, I am an old film, because he was filming on the battlefield, on the battlefield
接下來另外一個就是我們要做的,也是在,我是老影片,他因為在戰場拍攝,在戰場
So when shooting, there was no way to fix it at that time, because you can’t fix it in the battlefield, and the fixation is hit by the side.
所以拍的時候,那時候沒有辦法固定,因為在戰場你不能固定,固定是偏打到了
So while shooting, the bullets will fly over.
所以一邊拍就是子彈飛過來就對了
So it will have a lot of vibration problems like this
所以它就會有很多這樣的震動的問題
So let's take a look at the vibrating thing, it's probably like this
所以我們看一下這震動的東西大概是這樣
This is the one from the ship
這個是一個從艦艇上拍的那個
Taken from the top of the other car
從另外那個車廂上面拍到的
A car that vibrates like this above
一個上方這樣那震動的車子
how do we do this
那我們這個怎麼做呢
What we actually do is
我們這個其實做法是
We want to say something that can be shaken like this
我們希望說能夠把這樣被震動的東西
compensate it back
把它compensate回來
Look at the one next to it, everyone
你看各位看那張旁邊的
side shock absorber
旁邊的避震器
also absorb it
還把它吸收
just suck it up
就把它吸掉
very stable in the middle
中間就很穩定
Well, we should know better now
那其實我們現在應該比較了解
Why do rich people wait so long
為什麼有錢人會隔得不久
Because the rich man drives a double-avoidance car
因為有錢人他開的車子其實都是雙避的
The shock absorbers of the double avoidance are not good
雙避的避震都沒有好
That's more like my home
那像我家裡比較巧
I drive the clear suspension
我開那個明確避震
that is worse
那個比較差
You know there are a lot of shocks among us
你知道我們中間有很多避震
that many arrangements
那個很多安排
that's the sport
就是那個運動
jump over five will six
跳過去的五將六
But if you open the double V, it will be sucked up by righteousness
但是如果開雙V它是被正氣把它吸掉
So it can live 5 to 9
所以它就可以活得5到9
Because in fact, I often suspect that my internal organs are abnormal
因為其實我其實常常懷疑我的五臟有異位
good
好
That's probably how it's done here
那這裡做法大概是這樣
That is to say, this is how we do it
就是說我們做法是這樣
Because an X axis along with the time axis is called XT slice
因為一個X軸隨著時間軸就叫XT slice
Y axis This Y axis changes a Y slice with time
Y軸這個這一條Y軸隨著時間變化一個Y slice
Y軸YT slice
Y軸YT slice
So XT sliceYT slice
所以XT sliceYT slice
I seem to have gone very badly
我好像有去得很厲害
because it vibrates
因為它有振動
So we figured out how to use image processing
所以我們想辦法用影像處理的方法
Do Panel smoothing now
馬上做Panel smoothing
After bringing it back, the video was patched
再帶回來以後這影片就被修補了
just like
就好像
hot hills california have some houses
加州熱山機有一些房子
It is because after the earthquake
它因為大地震以後
It's designed like a sink
它就設計好像一個水槽這樣
put a lot of water in it
裡面放了很多水
Then
然後
When the earthquake comes
地震大地震來的時候
house didn't bite
房子都沒咬
It's the bucket of water biting
就是那一桶水在咬
Then take off these things
那這些東西用的就脫了
i put it
我把它
This will also come off
這上面也會脫了
fix it
把它固定住
right
對
so
這樣
I'm not necessarily right
我講的不一定對的
I just
我只是
it is sucked
它是被吸掉的
Then this is on the left and here is that
那這個左邊這裡是那個
On the right this is the one that was stabilized
右邊這是被stabilize的那個
The one on the left can jump
左邊這個是會跳的
On the right is the result of being stabilized
右邊這是被stabilize的結果
This is the way to fix the old one
這個就是可以去修復那個老的
Problem with video shake
影片震動的問題
there is another story
那這裡又有個故事
I will talk about this research with my students
這個研究我跟我學生講說
We come from this study
我們來自這個研究
Every study has a story to tell you
每一個研究都有個故事可以告訴你
this story first
這個故事先講
This Dr. Chen Dengyi is now
這個陳登毅博士現在是
Associate Professor of the Department of Virology at Raw University
原始大學的病毒系的副教授
he did very well
他做得非常好
Now a fast-track professor
現在已經一位快生教授
At that time it was my post-doc
那時候是我的post-doc
At that time, I did post-doc with me in the middle
那時候在中間跟我做post-doc
His Ph.D.
他交大的博士
This Dr. Chen is married
這個陳博士他結婚了
What about this topic?
那這個題目呢
This topic is like this
這個題目是這樣
just say
就說
Because I was in 2004 to 2008
因為我在2004到2008
From 2008 to 2001 I participated in a book
2008到2001我參加了一個書
Another program called Specialized Science
另外一個計劃叫做科專
Department of Mechanical Engineering
機制部的學界科專
His host is Cai Wenxiang, Vice President of Jiangdong University
他的主持人是江東大學的蔡文祥副校長
He is also the former president of Asia University
他也是亞洲大學的前校長
They are very strict, so he set us up
他們要求很嚴格,他就把我們訂好體
Therefore, for the financial plan, he pays the university himself as the main body
所以經濟費的計畫,他自己交大為主體
He stipulated that we say that you have to transfer one million in four years
他規定我們說你在四年內要計轉一百萬
In the past, I rarely thought of counting transfers.
以前我其實很少想到要去計轉
This part is well done, it doesn't really cost money
這部分做得很好,其實不需要錢
that's enough to make you happy
那個事已經讓你夠高興了
And he's busy and doesn't have time to spend money, and he's quite rich
而且那個忙沒有時間花錢也蠻有錢的
so you don't think about making money
所以你這樣沒有想到要去賺錢
But because the college stipulates you, and the Ministry of Economic Affairs stipulates you, you have to transfer
但是因為科專規定你,經濟部規定你,你要計轉
20% of the transferred money belongs to the Ministry of Economic Affairs
計轉的錢20%是規經濟部
The Ministry of Economic Affairs also needs to have performance
經濟部也要有業績
10% will stipulate that Kangdong University
10%會規定江東大學
Because I don't like messing with middle-aged homes, because you will be...
因為不喜歡弄弄中年院,因為會被你...
Because he can only give back 10%
因為他只能回饋10%
For me, if I do this project, if it is finished
對我來講,我做這個計畫如果做完的話
He gave me 70%, I can let the students go abroad
他給我70%,我就可以讓學生出國
let them do a lot of things
讓他們做很多的事情
What about Chen Dingyou?
那這個陳丁祐呢
One of the topics we did was to put a camera on the TV field
我們做的一個題目是一個在電視場上放一個攝影機
When the exhibition is going to be held, I hope to know when it will be on display for 8 hours today
要展覽的時候,希望知道今天8個小時在展覽的時候
How many people have watched this TV show, watched this advertisement, or this boost
有多少人來看過這個電視場,看過這個廣告,或者這個boost
So he must look here, then I count how many people there are
所以他一定要看這邊,那我算到底有多少人
Then you can’t double count, because if the count is inaccurate, the owner doesn’t want this advertising machine
那你不能重複算,因為算不準的話,業主不要這個廣告機
So this Chen Dengyi, at that time was in the business world in 2008
所以這個陳登義就,那時候是2008年營業界這個地方
Because he gave me 800,000 yuan, then I want to say, I thought at that time that the middle business was capable, and you were still very important
因為他給我80萬,那我想說,我那時候覺得中營業能,你還是很重要
So I told him, you can tell someone a good
所以我跟他講說,你可以講一個好丁的給人
I said tell him, if you can't do it, you don't need money
我說跟他講說,如果做不出來不要錢
But at that time, I was in business in 2008, and I made three post-docs to do this
但是那時候我就2008年營業,我就弄了三個post-docs做這個事情
Waiting for money is not enough, that is to say, one person and one group
等錢就不夠,就是說那個,一個做一個人一組
As far as Chen Dengyi and Chen Duo are in one group, the other two post-docs are in another group
就陳登義,陳多是一組,另外兩個post-docs另外一組
Actually there are two I know they can't do it because they are not the specialty
其實有兩個我知道他們做不出來,因為他們不是這個專長
I'm negative
我是負一片的
Ingredient moon
成分月
Don't let them do it in three months
不讓他們在三個月內要做出來
Because the business is going to be full
因為事業要展滿
so i just say
所以我就說
we are monday
我們禮拜一
your monday
你的禮拜一
we'll have a meeting
我們就開會
Manufacturers discuss here on Thursday
禮拜四這邊廠商討論
how to continue
到底要怎麼樣繼續做下去
Monday is an internal meeting
禮拜一是有內部開會
Monday I just need to see the DD of the composition month
禮拜一我只要看到成分月的DD
I don't even know it's over
我都不知道完了
then we will be in january
那我們就一月
It's almost New Year's Eve in January
一月那時候快過年了
January to February
一月到二月
I haven't made anything for a month
一個月都沒做出東西
Because we just wanted to be lazy
因為我們剛開始想偷懶
The one who wants Open Source
想要Open Source的那個
Make Decatur
Face Decatur
Then you can't use it
那你拿來都不能用
So we later actually
所以我們後來其實
We only do it for two months
我們只做兩個月的時間
just made it
就把它做出來了
That
那
Dr. Moon Cheng
成分月成博士
his wife
他太太
It didn't take long for their hearts to grieve
他們心悲痛沒有多久
Bi Xiao is still very small
畢小還是很小
that component month
那成分月
you know i'm on monday
你知道我就禮拜一
right or wrong
念成對不對
the meeting
開會
he monday
他禮拜一
you'll know he had a miserable saturday
你會知道他有很痛苦的禮拜六
that sunday
那禮拜天
every time he
他每次
His wife is more painful
他太太更痛苦
because he didn't eat that day
因為他那天沒吃
Take this camera home with you every month
成分月就帶著這個攝影機回家
he kept changing clothes
他就一直換衣服
Then his son kept changing clothes
然後他兒子也一直換衣服
That's dad going to test the system
就是爸爸要測試這個系統
is it good or not
到底好不好
I'm finally changing clothes
終於就在換衣服了
I'm called rescue, I'm a first-class rescuer, you see I'm so poor that I'm dying
我叫做營救的,做營救一等一門的,你看我窮的要死
And then tell me to keep changing clothes
然後還要叫我一直換衣服
So, but we made it four months, three months later
所以,但是我們四個月,三個月以後我們把它做出來了
we made it
我們把它做出來了
I won't go into the details, we'll just make it
我不要講細節,我們就做出來了
This is Chen Deying, Dr. Chen
這個就陳德映,陳博士
This is Xiao Deying, the Tangwei Hiroshi University that I just talked about, because of the one by Ilu Watson
這個是蕭德映,剛剛講的湯尾博大學,因為伊魯沃遜的那個
This is Dr. Sun, who is now at the University of the Arts, and his assistant is called
這是孫醫師博士,他現在在開的藝術大學,他用助理叫做
These guys, he's doing the test
這些人,他在做測試
that's probably it
大概就是這樣了
The result of the test is
測試的結果,就是
This is that year
這是那個當年那個
The thing just now was made in April of 2004 and 2008
剛才這個東西是2004、2008年的4月做出來的
made by the system
系統就做出來的
And then we get the end of the year
然後我們得到的那一年年底
Get Small Business Week of the Ministry of Economic Affairs
得到的經濟部周小企業
That product got the Weekly Small Business Contact Research Award
那這個產品得到的周小企業的接觸研究獎
2009 Typec Computex Typec Best Choice Award
2009年的Typec Computex Typec Best Choice Award
Really 800,000
就真的80萬
Then I also gave him the technology of this technology
然後我把這個技術的技術技術也給他
HG that environment company
HG那個環境公司
That's 800,000
就是80萬
That's the 800,000 he said
就是他講的80萬
You get paid when you make it
做出來的時候有收錢
That's the logo they won the award
那這是他們得獎的那個Logo
then this is an exhibition
那這個是展覽
Exhibition in April
4月的展覽
3 days from April 16th to 18th
4月從16號到18號3天
8 hours a day
每天8個小時
24 hours in total
總共24個小時
The environmental company sent two people down below
環境公司派了兩個人在下面
Calculate light out
算光出
Count how many people are right or wrong
算到底有多少人是對還是不對
90% accuracy
正確率90%
it's august
這是8月的時候
August 21 to 24
8月21到24
also 4 days
也是4天
7 days in total
總共有7天
It is also 90% correct in 6 hours
也是6個小時正確率90%
for ad groups
對廣告組來講
90 is the best number
90是最好的數字
you 150
你這個150
Because he only uses paperwork
因為他用文書而已
How much is it? 150 is too much
算多少錢?150太多了
90 is a little discount
90是打一點折
because it will not be too low
因為它會不會太低
50 like a toy
50跟玩具一樣
50 is not as good as counting with some battalions
50不如用點營的算
Okay, so that's what we did just now
好,那這剛剛就是我們做的這個
yes, just haven't finished
對,剛剛還沒講完
The most perfect future 80
最完美的以後80
70% people, 13% off
70%人,87折嘛
Because 20% goes to the Ministry of Economy
因為20%給經濟部
10% to Jiaotong University
10%給交通大學
so the toy comes with
所以玩具配
70% back to my lab
70%就回到我實驗室
I will give 200,000 to Chen Deng and Chen Shi
我就把20萬給陳登一陳都是
Then I had two conferences that year
然後我那個那年有兩個會議
one in germany and one in sielog
一個在德國一個在西澇
I will use the funds from our department
我就用我國科的經費
Let Dr. Chen Dengyi go to the meeting
讓陳登一博士去開會
Then take his wife with him
然後帶他太太一起去
I give him 200,000
我給他20萬
after going twice
去了兩次以後
After the meeting, his wife came back and asked him
會議以後他太太現在回來問他說
Do you have any plans?
還有沒有計畫
It's good to go abroad, right?
出國很好對不對
You can go abroad by sitting in the cinema
坐影院可以出國這樣
so sometimes it's like that
所以有時候就是這樣
it's fun it's fun it's here
就是好玩就是好玩在這裡
Most of you are very incomprehensible
你大部分都是很看不懂的
But you can change a lot of clothes to go abroad
但是衣服換很多可以出國的
sometimes good
有的時候也不錯
then next
那接下來
I just forgot to tell Rui
我剛剛忘記跟Rui講
What the hell are we doing at PinkPinkCondom
我們在就PinkPinkCondom到底幹什麼樣
It doesn't matter how long it is
它數有點長什麼關係
It counts a bit long relation like this
它數有點長的關係是這樣
Because I just said we got a lot of V streams
因為我剛剛講過我們收入了很多V流
Ditch type V flow inside BetaFace
Ditch types的V流在BetaFace裡面
we wish to say
我們希望說
quick search right?
快速搜尋對不對
If I have a way to quickly know about this V flow
如果我有辦法很快的知道說這個V流
calculation past
算過去
I know the clip that says this V flow
我知道說這個V流的片段
about how many people
大概有多少人的時候
I can do a quick search
我可以做一個快速搜尋
i can say ok
我可以說OK
We put so many V streams inside this clip
我們把這個片段裡面這麼多的V流
you find me
你給我找
There are too many clips with less than 10 people
有超多10個人以下的片段
find it for me
你給我找出來
In this case, it is a shooting group
這樣的話是一個出手群
So PinkPinkCondom is already important
所以PinkPinkCondom已經是很重要的
So we did another study here
所以我們在這裡又做另外一個研究
It is a method of Tutas to calculate
就是Tutas的一個方法去算
This algorithm is different
這個算法不太一樣
This is in front of that advertising machine
這個跟在那個廣告機前面
look different there
在那裡看是不一樣的
Because this place belongs to L780
因為這個地方是L780的
That is, how else can you tell me how many people are here?
就是說你還能告訴我這裡有多少人
You have to do the math for a while
你用算都要算一陣子
this place too
這個地方也是
how many people have to count
到底有多少人要算一下
it's difficult
這很困難
The reason for the difficulty is that usually the resolution of the cancoder is not good
難的原因是因為通常cancoder的解析度是不好的
Furthermore, crowds often have problems covering each other.
再來就是人群常常會有互相遮蔽的問題
Then the appearance is different, some people are squatting and some are standing
然後在外觀上不一樣,有些人蹲著有人站著
Some feet are in a hurry
有些腳踏著急著去
So there are many, many different questions
所以有很多很多不一樣的問題
Then do this thing I just said
那做這個東西我剛剛講過
It can do a search, that is, search for video information
它可以去做出收尋,就是對於視訊的出收尋
But it has other business opportunities
但是它還有其他的商機
What business opportunity?
什麼商機呢?
For example, here at this intersection
就是譬如說在這個路口這裡
If I put a cancoder here
我如果放一個cancoder在這裡
put one or two cancoder
放一兩cancoder
Then I know that now there are many
然後我知道現在有很多
I can do traffic control
我可以做traffic control
I can issue that traffic signal and say
我可以發出那個交通號字說
you can put it now, there are many more
你現在可以放,還有很多
Because there are a lot of tools here
因為現在有很多具在這裡
In MRT or when not to take a taxi
在捷運或者不打過的時機
It may have several scalators
它可能有好幾個scalator
defense ladder
就是辯護梯
if open anytime
如果隨時隨度都開過
It's actually very bad
其實是很不好的
So if I can use this way
所以我如果能夠用這樣的方式
To estimate how many legal persons
去估測大概有多法人的時候
or by MRT
或者是捷運出來
When there are multiple legal persons, I can only open one step or three steps
多法人的時候我可以只開一步或開三步
That's how you do crowd control
就是你這樣來做人流控制
so it will
所以它會
so many things
所以很多事情
Our approach is not to go into details
我們方法就是不要講細節
There are two PASS
就有兩個PASS
one is the part that counts
一個是算那個的部分
One is the part that requires learning tools
一個是要學具的部分
Because it is easier to see the picture
因為圖看比較容易
Our first pass is
我們第一個PASS是
We do not use BASS
我們是用不要BASS
Because it is impossible to use the human form to calculate
因為不可能去用人形去算
because it would be too slow
因為這樣算會算得太慢
because you're going to say
因為你要去說
here alone here alone
這裡一個人 這裡一個人
use a model to correct
用個模型去對的話
don't count too slowly
不要算起來太慢
So we treat a person as a bunch of people
所以我們是把一個人當作一坨人
Just a group of people is a bunch of people
就是一群人是一坨人
relatively large lump
比較大坨
Then a person is relatively small
然後一個人就是比較小坨
It is BLOCK
就是BLOCK
Use BLOCK's BASS method to calculate
用BLOCK的BASS的方法去算
So we're talking like this
所以我們這樣這一坨的話
there are two people here
這裡有兩個人
But because they cover each other
但是因為他們互相遮蔽
so he will
所以他會
In fact, its area will become smaller
其實他的面積會變小
will be deducted in the end
最後會扣掉
So in our second step
所以我們第二個步的時候
just add it back
就是把它加回來
Another one that will come out is
另外一個會多出來的是
in turn will be more
反過來會多出來
is the shaded part
就是有陰影的部分
if the shadow
如果陰影的時候
it was actually a person
它其實本來一個人
It becomes 1.4 1.5 people
就變成1.4 1.5個人
in this situation
在這種狀況之下
We are on the second pass
我們在第二個PASS
recycule
recycule
During the recycle part
recycule部分的時候
to buckle it back
要把它扣回來
So we devised some way to do
所以我們設計了一些方法去做
This is B's PASS
這是B的PASS
Then use Escender's Colonel
那用Escender的Colonel
there is some math don't tell this
有一些數學不要講這個
of course we need to know
那當然我們要知道
Gento in different locations
真托人在不同的位置
Because of that Perspective effect
因為有那個Perspective effect
So farther, closer
所以比較遠、比較近
it varies in size
它的大小都不一樣
So we're going to deal with these issues
所以我們要處理這些問題
no flat problem
沒有平的問題
This is B's PASS
這是B的PASS
even the shadow part
就算陰影的部分
As far as the part of Acclusion and shadow
就Acclusion跟陰影的部分
We have to find a way to add it back and get it back
我們要想辦法把它加回去撿回來
we are going to estimate this
我們要估測這個
How many people are there in Field View?
Field View裡面到底有多少人
How fast are we going?
那我們速度大概多快呢
10 sheets per second
是1秒鐘10張
10 pictures per second is actually more than a mistake
1秒鐘10張其實是錯錯有餘的
why
為什麼呢
because now i have to estimate
因為我現在我要估測
The government also wants this
政府也很希望這個
especially when exercising
尤其是全程運動的時候
How many people does the president actually have?
總統其實到底有多少人
how many people with him
有多少人跟他
sorry to say
不好意思講了
The police are actually looking for me
警察其實在找我這邊
use this suggestion
這個建議用一下
OK, let's see the results of the experiment.
好那我們看一下實驗的結果
Then of course we have to experiment with the best stuff
那我們當然要跟實驗的最好的東西
This paper is actually a topic that I mean is actually very applicable
這篇paper其實是 我的意思是說其實就這種還是很應用的題目
It's not that you can't get the best stuff
其實不是不見得能不能上最好的東西
Our paper is an air separation called ACM's Malhany UV
我們這個paper是上了一個叫ACM的Malhany UV的空分
Its Rooge UV is probably less than S
它Rooge UV大概不到S
This Longpaper
這個Longpaper
It's actually a pretty good paper
它其實是一個很好的一個論文
Then let's compare it to the best interpretation
那我們讓它跟詮釋的最好的東西比
What I want to explain is that people count
我要詮釋的是人算
It's a yellow line wait a minute and you'll see a micro Curve
它是用黃色的線 等一下你會看到一個微Curve
Then if there is a State of the Art called Gaussian Process
那如果有一個State of the Art 是叫做Gaussian Process
Use Green Green Curve
用Green 綠色的Curve
Then From A to G it is used to have a Curve
然後From A to G它是用有一個Curve
Then our method we use Blue Curve
然後我們的方法我們是用Blue Curve
So wait a minute and see if Blue is the closest to Red
所以等一下你仔細看到Blue跟Red是不是最接近
just know if our result is the best
就知道我們結果是不是最好
Then we use two KMalhany
那我們用兩個KMalhany
so you can take a look
所以你可以看一下
It is walking these four lines, four curves are walking
它在走這四條線 四個Curve在走
The blue and red lines are actually close together
藍色的跟紅色的線其實是貼緊在一起的
The yellow and green lines are farther apart
黃色跟綠色的線就離得比較遠
I don't necessarily share too much
我不一定Share的太多
I only share the easier one
我只Share方面那個比較輕鬆
This Benchmark is UXD, which is what Shengli Diego learned from them, and it is one of several Cameras made
這一個Benchmark是UXD,就是勝利亞哥學他們做的,有幾個Camera造出來的其中一個
They want to do experiments, so they use Benchmark, so everything has to be compared with them
他們要做實驗,所以他們就用Benchmark,所以所有東西都要跟他們比
Use this thing as a base, and then compare it to something else
用這個東西當基礎,然後就跟別的東西比
Wait a minute, he has a lot of places suddenly wrapped up by one person, you can take a look
等下人,他有一個人很多地方突然就包起來,各位可以看一下
Our method is the closest to that light place.
我們的方法都是跟那個光處是最接近的
People start to pack up now, just a group of people
人現在開始包起來,就一群人
He has about 10 pictures per second, and the original speed is 30 pictures per second
他一秒鐘大概10張,一秒鐘本來的速度是30張
We can probably count 10, so he should actually be pretty close to an appointment
我們大概可以算10張,所以他其實應該算很接近約談
enough for one second
夠用了,一秒鐘
It is enough to report two records
報告兩張記錄就夠了
this is my last sentence
這是我最後一句要講的東西
You can't talk about this
這個東西你不可能講出來
does it matter
到底有沒有關係
In fact, when we were a little long in this book,
其實我們在這書有點長的時候
We have to deal with a lot of content
我們要處理很多的content
is the content
就是內容
So if I can randomly lock in
那如果我能夠隨機鎖進去
like say
就像說
I said the eyes in martial arts movies
我說武俠片裡面的眼睛
I don't know if you watch martial arts movies
我不知道你們看不看武俠片
The brightest thing about martial arts movies is
武俠片那個最燈彈的就是
In fact, a Jianxia
其實一個建俠
He just made that one thousand and two yuan
他就把那個做一千兩塊
the best
最厲害
The most powerful Jianxia may use a builder
最厲害的建俠可能用建器
The most powerful thing is to use the builder
很厲害的就是用建器
the kind that weakens you
那種給你削弱的
The most powerful thing is to use liquid surface
最厲害的就是用液面
soon everyone
各位,很快
so we do anything
所以我們做任何東西
just a mirror
就是一個印鏡
do not make a mirror
不做一個印鏡
That is, who is stronger
就是說誰比較厲害
then we will do now
那我們現在要做
to do one thing
要把做一件事情
Let's talk about what you're going to do now
我們現在先講一下你們要做什麼
you have no command
你們沒有指揮
It doesn't matter
沒關係
That Ye Zehua here
這裡那個葉澤華
just now i can't say one
剛剛我不能講一個
Ye Zehua is not here
葉澤華也不是在這裡
There is a very important wave in the middle
中間有一塊很重要的波子
I'm done now
我現在都做出來了
That's what we think now
那我們現在想法是這樣
I won't correct me it's okay
我不會指正沒關係
Let's move in front of a camera now
我們現在先比到一個攝影機前面
compare with
跟比一下
just compare it
就比就可以了
But it doesn't matter if you do numbers
但做數字都快都沒關係
casual
隨便
But I was going to make it last now to say
但是我本來現在最後做出來就是說
you can conduct any music
你可以指揮任何音樂
Speed ​​size
快慢大小
I'll make you in a second
我等一下就把你弄成
can be like this
都可以這樣子
But it seems like you're directing this
但是好像是你在指揮這樣子
But the final question is a bit more difficult
但是終於的問題就有點困難了
Then our first step is to deal with
那我們第一步要處理就是說
From two-dimensional space to three-dimensional space
從二度空間到三度空間之間
There is a big Gab
有很大的Gab
take a look everyone
各位看一下
This is the size of Gb
這是二圍的把Gb
This is what we hope to use Kinnet
這是我們希望用Kinnet
on the microphone
那麥克風上面
Scalaton sequence captured by Kinnet
Kinnet抓出來的Scalaton sequence
we want it to become
我們希望它變成
Two things
二圍的東西
hope it turns into something with measurements
希望它變成三圍的東西
Then it becomes the action of the skeleton block
那再會變成骨架塊的動作
But finally there's a big Gab
但是終於有很大的Gab
It's just using the two-circle thing
就是用二圍的東西
What's around again is actually
再三圍的東西其實
scared
怕的
if it is large
如果是很大的
Then we want to say that this two-dimensional thing
那我們希望說把這個二維的東西
I just because I was talking I took a
我剛剛因為我是在講說我拍了一個
also such a thing
也這樣一個東西
Wait a minute to conduct all kinds of different music
等一下要去指揮各種不同的音樂
Of course, we need to deal with three-dimensional
那當然需要處理用三維的
After the three-dimensional estimation comes out and then goes back
三維的估測出來又再回頭去
to manipulate the action
去操縱這個動作
You're the only one who can manipulate. It's beautiful. It's great.
你才有辦法操縱很漂亮很棒
So there's one in the middle that we need to fill up
所以這中間有個我們需要把它填平
So we do it in two ways
那所以我們就分兩路進行
Ye Zhehua, Dr. Ye has someone who taught him
葉哲華 葉博士那邊有一個教他說
Skip over first Skip 2D to 3D
先跳過去 跳過二維到三維
Just use Kinet Microsoft KINET
就直接用Kinet Microsoft KINET
directly
直接就
Because of Microsoft KINET when he shoots he can
因為 Microsoft KINET他拍的時候他可以
can shoot
可以拍
It is RGB is the usual RGB sequence
就是RGB就是平常的RGB sequence
Square sequence with DEVS
跟DEVS的Square sequence
跟Square sequence
跟Square sequence
All three can be shot
三個都可以拍了
But it has a property that its distance
但是它有個性質就是它的距離
Or within three years and five meters
或者三年五公尺以內
Only then can you shoot well
才可以拍得好
So it is impossible for us to have every sequence such as
所以我們不可能每一個 sequence 比如說
Of course we
當然我們這個
you like that
你這樣那種
It's okay to be in front of a certain camera like that
這樣在某個攝影機前面那樣那是可以的
because it sure can shoot
因為它肯定可以拍
That Kinel is more expensive
那Kinel比較貴
you can use an ordinary video camera
你可以用一個普通的攝影機
it's best if you can do it
就可以做的話是最好
Then what we Kinel will do is
那我們Kinel會做的是
How to fill the relationship between the two and the three
怎麼樣填補這二個跟三個的關係
That
那
for example
舉例說
I am using Kinel here
我這裡是用Kinel
Catch this person's RGB sequence
抓到這個人的RGB sequence
Is there DAPS
有沒有DAPS
this is the depth
這是深度
This is the Spalding sequence
這是Spalding sequence
that I just said
那剛剛我講過
its greatest difficulty is its distance
它的最大的困難就是它的距離
Must be within 3.5 meters
必須要3.5公尺內
Now we have a question, which is
那我們現在有個問題就是說
I ask my classmates to help
我就請同學生大家幫忙
Everyone in our laboratory will go to exercise
我們實驗室大家會去運動一下
is to do various actions
就是做各種不同的動作
MultiNet
MultiNet
grab two angles
抓兩個角度
one is 0 degrees
一個是0度
one is 45 degrees
一個是45度
is this 45 degrees
這是45度嗎
right
沒錯吧
45 degrees
45度
these two angles
這兩個角度
Because everyone acts differently
因為大家都做不同的動作
do a lot like
做很多像的
I remember I went jumping around that day too
我記得我那天也去跳來跳去
this is me
這個就是我
student score student score
學生分數學生分數
Actually when I
其實我的時候
teacher, you go back
老師你往後走
Go forward
往前走
jump up
跳上去
climb down like this
爬下去這樣
stop that
那要把那個停下來
pat this thing straight
拍直撐這個東西
good
好
that's how we think
那我們想法就這樣
I can use RGB, because the RGB system does not have the 3.5 meter one
我能用RGB,因為RGB系統它沒有3.5公尺的那個
Usually because of my Pinet it will build this DataFace
通常因為我Pinet它會建這個DataFace的時候
Its limit is 3.5 meters on one side
它的限制是要3.5公尺一面
But my video just happens to be
但是我那個影片它剛好是
I didn't have Pinet at all when I was doing it
我在做的時候根本沒有Pinet
Then it has an RGB that is a Sequence of 2 degrees
那它有一個RGB就是2度這樣的Sequence
how do i use it to tune
我怎麼樣利用它去調語
to the corresponding action
調到對應的動作
Then by the way, you can use its depth and its skeleton
然後順便可以利用它的深度跟它的骨架
Use these actions
這些動作拿來用
This is my idea
這是我的想法
So what we do is say
所以我們做法就是說
I first use the RGB system to tune
我先用RGB系統去調語
You can use it at the same time after you transfer it
調到以後就同時可以用它的
Depth and Skeleton Information
深度跟Skeleton的Information
It's not that easy to do this
要做這個事情不是那麼容易
If you want to use RGB and UDAVS Information at the same time
你如果說想同時用RGB跟UDAVS的Information的話
Its two marking systems and its Future Space are different
它的兩個做標系統它的Future Space是不一樣的
So we have to go through a program called Communical
所以我們必須透過一個叫做Communical
Communical Coordination Analysis
Communical Coordination Analysis
Bring these two marking systems into a standard marking system
把這兩個做標系統帶到一個正規範的做標系統
These we can use
這些我們才能夠用到
use two things together
兩個東西一起用
it's a must do
這是一個一定要做的事情
Then with this we can see
那有了這個以後我們就可以看
You can take a look
各位可以看看
Yesterday, these two people were far away, right?
昨天這個兩個人很遠對不對
He is over 3.5 meters
他超過3.5公尺
One is to search out in Check
一個是在Check搜掉
One is Cross-on
一個是Cross-on
Then we use these two Sequence
那我們就用這兩個Sequence
To call DataBase
去調DataBase
Corresponding RGB Sequence
對應的RGB Sequence
Bax that we can use it later
對到以後我們就可以用它的Bax
let's just say
我們就這裡就說
OK I use CheckWatch
OK 我用CheckWatch
Then I can we get from the DataBase
那我就可以我們從DataBase
Get the first year, the second year, the third year
拿到第一年第二年第三年
Then this Cross-on
那這個Cross-on
You can also get the first year, the second year and the third year
也可以拿到第一年第二年第三年
i fell out
我當掉出來
fall out first year
第一年掉出來
or fall out the next year
或第二年掉出來
it's all close action
它都是很接近的動作
Then we can use it at the same time
那我們就可以同時用它的
Depth and its Skeleton stuff
深度跟它的Skeleton的東西
to do the following
來做下面要做的事情
mine is
我這部是
Ours is filling the second dimension
我們這部是在填補二度空間
Cang Min between the three-dimensional space
跟三度空間之間的倉敏
OK, let me give you an example
好 那我舉個這個例子
Does this have a T?
那這個有沒有T
OK
OK
Then you can adjust its depth and its Skeleton T action
那你就可以調到它的深度跟它的Skeleton T的動作
Then there is this thing that is very useful
那有的這個東西就很好用
Why? Because after some actions
為什麼?因為有的這個動作以後
We can use it to change the size of its movement and its speed
我們就可以拿去改變它的運動的大小跟它的快慢
The size adjustment of the speed is to use the mood of the music
那個快慢的大小調整,就是用音樂的情緒
So this project is actually a combination of many professors.
那所以這個計畫其實是結合了很多教授做的
That is, the previous one from 2D to 3D is based on self-created things, and the neighbor is cooperating with Dr. Neighbor
就是前面那個從2D到3D是跟自創的東西有那個鄰居與鄰博士合作
Then, of course, my Ph.D. will study, and the housekeeper has joined
然後當然那個我的博士會研究有那個看家棟有加入
And then the emotional part of the music
然後接下來就音樂情緒的部分
Here I will talk about the results they tuned out.
這裡我就講一下他們調出來的結果
The results we call out are all better than State or be R
我們調出來的結果都比State or be R
So Pay here is actually on Igboe's Generation
所以這邊Pay的其實已經快上Igboe's Generation
If there is an IP, I will skip it
有IP,我把它跳過去好了
Then what we have next, the next step is how to get it
那接下來我們有的這個東西,接下來下一步要做的是怎麼樣去
Because some of us already have Skeleton
因為我們有的已經有Skeleton
But it this Skeleton is music
但是它這個Skeleton是音樂的
Because you just came to measure like this
因為剛剛你這樣來量拍的
OK, that Squad
好,那個Squad
then i want to change now
那我現在想要改變
then it directs all kinds of music
那它就指揮各種音樂
Because the beat of the music will be different
因為音樂的節拍會不一樣
The form of music will be different
音樂的形式會不一樣
so the size will be different
所以會大小會不一樣
So we're going to analyze the mood of the music
所以我們要去分析音樂情緒
You ask me what kind of music mood analysis
你問我說音樂情緒什麼科分析
Musical mood can be analyzed
音樂情緒是可以分析的
I said advanced moves are bigger
我說高級動作大一點
Sometimes it's weird to be angry
有時候生氣動作就奇怪一點
Well, we happen to have a research assistant at the Capital Innovation Center.
那我們資創中心剛好有一個研究助研究員
Yang Yuxuan
叫楊玉軒
He happened to be working on this part
他剛好在研究這個部分
so we have to bring him over
所以我們有把他要過來
let's get him together
我們就請他湊在一起
The hardest part is saying
那最難的部分是說
How do I go super power this exclusive
我怎麼樣去超能這個獨家
super power this exclusive
超能這個獨家
make it faster, slower, bigger, smaller
讓它變快變慢變大變小
That's why I made a book about Master Wu
那這就是我做了一本武大師
I just lost a Robardis book
就是我丟了一本羅巴迪斯的書
I lost a book of songs, songs, songs
我丟了一本樂歌、樂歌、樂歌
He didn't miss it when he came
他在來沒有丟解
I just throw him a book
我就丟一本書給他
music book
音樂的書
That was when I was studying in America in 1985
那是我1985年在美國念書的時候
A textbook was used to read Robardes
念羅巴迪斯用了一本教科書
Inside Inverse Kinematics
裡面有Inverse Kinematics
Wait a minute and I'll tell you about Kinematics for music
等一下我跟你們講音樂的 Kinematics
I know I need to solve this thing
我知道說要解這個東西
rely on that thing
要靠那個東西
just throw it to him
就丟給他
Unexpectedly, he made it in two months
結果沒想到他兩個月就做出來了
He is very smart, he saw this committee, he went to find similar software on the Internet
他很聰明,他就出看本委員,他就去網路上找的類似軟體
He just found one, and he modified it as soon as he changed it.
他就找到一個,那更一動他就把它修改一下就動了
so he finished it quickly
所以他很快就做完了
Then I changed the movement, the size and the rhythm of the music
接下來就是我改變了動作,大小跟音樂節奏
This is the tutor, right?
這是輔教對不對
Well, it seems to me that four months and three months are enough.
那我那看起來四個月三個月就夠了
So I threw these well-made assistant teachers to the professors of Tsinghua University
所以我就把這些做好的輔教丟給清華大學的教授
It is the constant fruit, let him change the original tation
就是那個諸恆果,叫他把原來的那個tation
Just pasting the stance of the body so that it doesn't change visually
就是身體的tation貼上去,讓他視覺上看起來是沒有改變的
this is what we do
這是我們做的事情
Then I teach, we just did it like this, this is done casually, this is my student, he is in music
那我修教,我們剛剛就這樣,這是隨便做的,這是我的學生,他在音樂啦
so he looks good commanding
所以他指揮起來看起來很好
This is casual music, just ask him to conduct
這是隨便音樂音樂,叫他指揮就對了
Just according to the concept I just had, we use the mood of the music
就按照我剛剛的概念,我們用音樂的情緒
because we need to keep quiet
因為我們要小聲
this is pasted
這是貼上去的
it just didn't move
它剛剛手沒有舉動到
move now
現在有舉動到
This is what we hope to say
這就是我們希望說把
you just think it's over
你隨便以為完
Might be able to get a product in the future
以後可能也可以弄個商品
maybe you're getting bored
可能你弄得越來越無聊
So it's not bad for you to go back and get this
所以你回去弄這個也不錯
you go live that
你去直播那個
The product with six points
背六分的那個商品
Is the live broadcast good or not?
直播的有沒有樣也蠻好的
and you
那你
What you have to do
What you have to do
right in front of my camera
就是在我攝影機面前
no casual comparison
沒有隨便比比
we'll figure it out
我們就想辦法
make different music
弄成不同的音樂
race by statue
靠雕像賽
that is
就是
Anyway it is
反正就是
Is it right?
有沒有樣就對了
good
好
for this part i think i will
那這個部分我想我就
I won't talk too much about the details
細節的部分我就不要講太多
I just want to achieve the result
我就想做到的結果
Because this part is a little bit involved
因為這個部分有一點牽涉到
what i just said
我剛剛講的
Problems with Inverse Kinematics
Inverse Kinematics的問題
That's because I'm telling you why its trajectory matters
那因為我跟你講為什麼它軌跡很重要
Because when we command, our hands are in space, right?
因為我們指揮的時候手在空間的話對不對
The mine disaster is said because its trajectory
說的礦難是因為它軌跡
How is this trajectory determined?
這個軌跡怎麼決定呢
you have a dead body here
就是你這裡有個屍體
A digger looks like a corpse with a digger
一個挖把像一個挖把的屍體
If you are in space, there are still a few points
你在空間的話還有幾個點
When you use one point of its constitution to count back the round
你用一個點它體質回算回合的時候
your light festival place its angle
你的光節的地方它的角度
can be counted
都可以算得到
What about diggers
那對挖把來講的話
The angle of your light festival must conform to the
你這個光節的角度必須要符合在這個反應
the same for people
對人也一樣
Then in human rights you are
那在人體公權你就
This place might have a wiping attitude
這個地方可能會有抹的態度
So when you look at this path planning
所以你看這個路徑規劃的時候
When coming down the same road
原路這樣下來的時候
In fact, this angle and this angle
事實上這個角度跟這個角度
is always changing
是一直在改變的
Then we can use
那我們可以用
U-IN-LESS
U-IN-LESS
Call IN-LESS-KIMATICS round count
叫IN-LESS-KIMATICS回合算
So here are the angles
所以這裡有角度各多少
how many here
這裡各多少
to the next point
到下一個點的時候
how much can i calculate this angle
我可以算這個角度多少
how much is this point
這個點多少
So it's a little bit mathematically frequent
所以它有一點數學頻密
Then, in order to keep its speed relatively controllable
那我們為了要讓它速度能夠比較控制住
Because there is an angle change
因為有一個角度變
Calculate its speed so it doesn't flatten
計算它的速度讓它不要平緩
This, this, this, at least it looks like this, but this, well, that's a function of Jacobian, well, let's see first,
是這樣,這樣,這樣,至少看起來像這樣,不過這樣,好,那這是 Jacobian的功能,好,那我們先看一下,
This is the practitioner method. Dr. Ye found out a piece of software, and then he improved it himself. Originally, Wei Wo could improve it.
這就是業者法,業博士找出來的一個軟體,然後他自己把它改善,本來威窩可能把它改善,
Because the one on the left is also the original, not the Skeleton caught by Kinio, he only has the Skeleton to click,
因為左邊這也是原來的,不是Kinio抓到的Skeleton,他只有Skeleton能點,
So we use Jieshi's method to find an array. After we have this array,
所以我們用介石法的方法找一個數組,有了這個數組以後,
His problem becomes analyzable Egnatic, so I can plan his path,
他這個問題變成可分析Egnatic,所以我就可以去規劃他的路徑,
You are so fast and slow, I can do it big or small, okay, then this is the path I just talked about, using Inverse
你這樣快慢,大小我都可以做,好,那這個就是我剛剛講的路徑,用Inverse
Maybe the ities will go back, and the part of Midzidimotion is like this, that is to say, Dr. Yang Yuxuan, who I occasionally serve,
可能ities化回去,那Midzidimotion的部分是這樣,就是說這個我偶爾配服的楊玉軒博士,
Because it can still be divided into secret systems, that is, he has a few superficial studies but wants to talk about Tension,
因為還可以分那麼密系,就是他有幾個表面學卻要說Tension,
Tension, tension, activity, he wants to be active, and then Valence, it becomes different,
張度,緊張度,Activity,他要吃個活躍,然後Valence,就變成不同的,
That means that in music,
那意思就是說在音樂裡面,
when each note is played
每一個音符播出來的時候
It can fall all over it's called
它都可以落在整個它的這叫
Affective Space
Affective Space
is the space of emotion
就是感情的空間
so your current situation
所以你現在情境
You're taking advantage of my brother again in every tone
你又趁哥的在每一個音調
can't be destroyed here
都可以滅不到這裡
Why are you happy and angry now?
你現在是高興生氣幹嘛
He quantifies it in this Space
他把它量化在這個Space裡面
and this thing
而且這個東西
We use two-dimensional things to explain
我們用二維維的東西來解釋
There is no sound during this time
這時間裡面的時候沒有聲音
so it is 0 at distance
所以它在距離是0
it's time 1
它這個時間1的時候
Its Venom is positive
它的Venom是正的
Its Arrow So is positive a little bit
它的Arrow So是正的一點點
it will be here
它都會在這裡
T equals 2 will be here
T等於2都會在這裡
T equals 3 will be here
T等於3都會在這裡
In this so-called Affectual
在這個所謂的Affectual
Affectual in the Space
Affectual in the Space
Affectual Space
Affectual Space
It's that emotional space
就是那個感情的Space
Emotional Space
感情的Space
Then if it counts the distance
那如果把它算距離
The distance at which time can meet the origin
時間能夠遇到原點的距離
it can become like this
就可以變成這樣子
that its size
那它大小
Intensity can be used to command
Intensity就可以用來指揮的
Strength
強度大小
So use this way
所以用這樣的方式
we see clips of docs doing
我們看到博士做的片段
Everyone see there is a wall
各位看到這裡有牆壁
It waits to see that the walls will change
它等一下看到牆壁會變
there are walls
有牆壁
The student he was wearing black was a bit of a fraud
那學生他當時穿黑色衣服是有點詐騙的
us
我們
Because in fact, in this process, I
因為其實這個過程我就
I'll show you all
我去給大家看一下
What we have now is this original version
我們現在有的是這一個原來的版本
It will have Dex Data
它會有Dex的Data
Then to Skeleton
然後再到Skeleton
Then we're going to use Skeleton to do it
那我們要用Skeleton去做
We're going to grab some key Skeletons
我們要把一些關鍵的Skeleton抓出來
Then take the three spaces I had
然後再把我原來有的三個空間
The Front of the second space pushes it up
二個空間的Front把它推上去
try to push up
盡量推上去
and then to analyze its shadowing
然後去分析它的遮蔽
because when we command
因為我們會指揮的時候
It turns out that when the movement is relatively small, the cover is less
原來動作比較小的時候遮蔽比較少
But when you move a lot, the covered area will exceed the original things
但是你動作大的時候遮蔽的範圍就會超過原來有的東西
Then all I had was something like this
那我原來只有這樣的東西
But what I'm dealing with the best stuff is
但是我要處理最好的東西的是
where is there no
有什麼地方是沒有的
Then how do I have the same problem as before?
那我怎麼樣跟剛剛的問題一樣
How do I go and where to grab the proper material
我怎麼樣去哪裡抓到適當的資料
put it there
把它放在那個地方
Make your visual look as if it's real
讓你這視覺上看起來好像真的一樣
Then I will affect the speed of its command with such words
那用這樣的話我就會影響它的指揮的速度
The size of these issues
指揮的大小這些問題
so I can match the rhythm
所以我就可以配合節奏
to conduct different symphonies
去指揮不同的交響去
Then I just changed the 2D to 3D thing to Skep it
那我剛剛把2D到3D的東西把它Skep掉一些
Then this is the so-called 2n and 2d
那這就是所謂的2n和2d
A processing method of 2.5d
2.5d的一個處理方法
Let me refute it first. The left side is the original one, and the right side is pasted up.
那我先駁一下,這左邊是原來的,右邊是貼上去的
well, this is now
好,這個現在是
Take a look at changing its amplitude
看一看改變它的 amplitude
That is, I can change its amplitude, which is smaller this time
就是我可以改變它的 amplitude,這次比較小
The action is relatively small, this time
動作比較小,這次比較
It's more delicate, you can just put it down
比較秀氣的,只可以放下來
Alright, the one with the bigger movement this time will only be put down
好,那這次動作比較大的,只會放下來
Synthetic this time
這次是合成的
Okay, let me refute first, at this time
好,那我先駁一下,這個時候
Then the next thing is its speed
那接下來就是它的快慢
Of course it is not the
當然它不是把那個把
It's not engraved, but you can see it's already in place
不是刻的,但是你看它已經對象了
ok , this is faster
好,這是動作比較快的
that's all
就這樣
Here's where we're looking at its limits to a painting
這是我們在看它的極限到一個畫
How much is the angle, it will die
角度到多少,就會死翹翹
This is a group of rabbits, it's a little strange that they wear different clothes
這是一群兔,它穿的不一樣衣服就有點怪怪的
If it's 30 degrees
那如果到了30度的時候
It can be seen from here
從這裡就可以看出來
I can still talk about a third decade
我還可以講第三個十年
Many questions are constantly sung
很多問題都是不斷地演唱出來
so what do you think
所以那你覺得
It's about people's life
這關人就說是人生發揮
It is about people saying that life plays its role
那關人就說人生發揮
bright future
光明的未來
it depends on how you see yourself
那看你怎麼看你自己
you like to solve these problems
你喜歡解決這些問題
you are full of bright future
你就是充滿了光明的未來
won't you like it
你會不喜歡的嗎
Then I finally want to talk about my other thing
那我最後我想講一下我另外一個東西
Every hand has that giblet paper
各個手上都有那個內臟紙
The viscera paper, let me explain to you
內臟紙其實我跟大家解釋一下
That was ten years ago ten years ago
那是十年前十幾年前
that once my daughter
那個有一次我女兒
I was in elementary school when I was very young
那時候很小就小學了我
She sometimes comes home and asks me
她有時候回家問我說
Dad has a kid in the next class
爸爸那個隔壁班有一個孩子
she has no money for lunch
她沒有錢吃中飯
I said why no money
我說為什麼沒錢
She said her mom gave her 10 bucks a week
她說她媽媽一星期給她10塊錢
So it took her two days to die this class
所以她兩天才能死這班
I said so
我說是這樣
so I
我就
I happened to be at that time
那時候我剛好
what did they choose me to be parents will pay my parents
她們把我選成什麼家長會付我家長
So I ran to the next class and asked the teacher
所以我就跑去隔壁班問問老師
So this child I helped her teach
所以這個孩子我就幫她教了
But in the future, I will ask the school like this
可是未來我這樣學校去問說
how many children does she have
到底她有多少小孩子
have such a problem
有這樣的問題
Because when I figured it out, there were ten or twenty students in the school.
因為我一弄起來學校裡面有十幾二十的學生
like this
是這樣子
so i go back to the lab
所以我就回到實驗室
I tell my students
我就跟我學生講
do him a favor
跟他做一件好事吧
Then
然後
then my relatives
然後跟我的親戚
and my colleagues
還有跟我同事
My colleague has several colleagues
我的同事有幾個同事
what female robot
什麼女機人啊
Gao Mingda
高明達啊
those I said again
那些我又講
i scraped together some money
我又湊一些錢
and let these twenty children
然後讓這些二十個孩子
I will be compensated by tutors from all classes.
都有課會補習生的補償給我
all the money like this
所有的錢這樣
but it didn't work for me
但是我沒有用
A house for a group of uncles and aunts who love you
一群愛你們的叔叔阿姨的房子
Then this article is
那這篇文章是
I was
我那時候
they thank me
他們謝謝我
thank us with a card
謝謝我們用一張卡片
thank us
謝謝我們
I write
我寫的
Written in the name of a group of uncles and aunts
用一群叔叔阿姨的名義去寫的
That
那
this poem is
這一首詩是
That our Editor
那個我們的那個Editor
English Editor
英文Editor
English poems he gave me
他送給我的英文詩
I translate it into Chinese
我把它翻成中文
and then give it to these kids
然後就送給這些孩子
That
那
when i was studying
我那時候唸書的時候
when i went to the interview
我去面試的時候
my advisor
我的指導教授
i am him
我是他
I was the first PhD student
我當初是第一個博士團學生
I don't know how long he will let me read
那也不知道他會讓我念多久
Actually I don't know
其實我不知道
But many students who go to Taiwan
但是很多台灣去的學生
Students who go to mainland China will find an American professor
大陸去的學生都會去找一個美國教授
Because American professors graduated in three years and six years
因為美國教授三年六畢了
when you read for a long time
那當你念了很久
How did I get my doctorate?
我博士怎麼念了
Two years for master's degree, five years for Ph.D.
碩士兩年博士念了五年
that sometimes it seems really
那有時候看起來真的覺得
Am I really that far behind?
我真的差那麼多嗎
feeling
感覺上
Then one day I went to my teacher
那時候有一天我去找我老師
I tell you
我告訴你
will you care about him
你會不會管他
You see their standard is only this
你看他們的標準只有這樣
my standard is here
我標準在這裡
just do it well
你就好好做
later i graduated
後來我畢業了
He told me actually
他跟我講說其實
He shoots so high
他標準射這麼高
Actually you crawl slowly
其實你慢慢爬爬爬
when climbing here
爬到這裡的時候
He lowered the standard and said you graduated
他就降下標準說你畢業了
but you should be here
但是你應該在這裡
i found out that
我發現說
So this is what it looks like
原來這個是這樣子
I'll look at this first
我先看看這個
Why does my project kind of look like
為甚麼我的項目有點像
This is the most concrete manifestation of a young life
這個一個年輕的生命最具體的表現
It's the courage to stun Han in the tiger water and blood
就是在虎水跟血液當中暈韓的勇氣
He may encounter many setbacks
他也許會遭遇許多挫折
his will
他的意志
But his will will not be broken
但他的意志不會被擊垮
If life is a learning process
如果生命是一個學習的過程
He represents our greatest gain
他代表我們最大的收穫
It is how to grow up in setbacks
就是如何在挫折中成長著狀
look at the diamonds
看看鑽石
This is the most important
這是最重要的
It is a product of extreme high pressure
它是在極端高壓下的產物
if less stress
如果壓力少一點
it might just be crystal
它可能只是水晶
if only less stress
如果壓力再少一點
it may be a phase
它可能是靈態
it may just be soil in general
它可能只是一般的土壤
so if my teacher didn't treat me like that
所以如果我的老師沒有對我那樣的話
I can't be a central researcher long term today
我今天沒有辦法做中央研究員長期
There is no way to talk about three decades of research
也沒有辦法講三個十年的研究
able to last so long
能夠持續這麼久
I often tell my students about this
那個我有常常跟我學生講這個東西
就是good judgment comes from experience
就是good judgment comes from experience
experience comes from the judgment
experience comes from the judgment
very interesting
很有意思吧
your experience is from
你的經驗是從
Your good judgment is due to experience
你的好的判斷能力是因為經驗
your experience
你的經驗
Because of your wrong judgment in the past
因為你過去錯誤的判斷
it's coming
就來了
so we often fail
所以我們常常會失敗
but fails if
但是失敗如果
he can't handle your experience
他不能對付你的經驗
deal with what beats you
對付把你打敗的
words of a reason
的一個原因的話
If it fails, it fails to express
那失敗就有表達失敗了
Okay, thank you
好 謝謝
any questions
有沒有問題
I tell you it's a great show
我跟你講很精采的演長
Thank you teacher for a very wonderful performance
謝謝老師非常精采的演長
I'm not sorry
我不不好意思
I may not have understood just now
我剛剛可能沒有聽得懂
it's about that
就是關於那個
a person in action
一個人在動作
But save a lot in the middle
但是中間省掉很多
It’s the place where a lot of friends lost
就是掉了很多的FRIEND那個地方
The teacher mentioned that there are many points
老師提到的是說有很多點
Then there is a line in the middle
然後中間有一條線
When the middle line is gone, the dot is still there
那中間線沒有的時候點還在
So you can grab back a line with the highest score
所以可以抓回一個分數最高的線
give the action...
把動作都給...
not point
不是點
In fact, he was
其實他那個在
One of the short sides fully seamed
全縫短面的一個
A point of feature space
feature space的一個點
It's actually a very complicated point
其實是一個很複雜的點
Cover it with a Shape Context to describe many things
用一個Shape Context蓋上去描述很多東西
It is something described by one Beam and many Beams
它是用一個Beam 很多Beam去描述的東西
So it uses a very simple
所以它可是用一個很簡單的東西
to describe that point
去描述那個點
Unlike our simple math above a three-way empty
不像我們簡單的數學上面一個三路空
Just use a point conversion
用一個點的轉換而已
it is actually a description
它其實是一個描述
It is described with a Shape Context
它是用一個Shape Context下去描述
This description is very complicated
這種描述是很複雜的描述
It can describe the gesture very precisely.
它可以很精準的描述這個姿態
where is it falling
它在落在哪個位置
because when we act
因為我們動作的時候
action is like this in action
動作是這樣在動作
When I cover it with this
我用這個蓋上去的時候
It can be used with different relations
它可以用不同的關係
Described by the ring-by-ring Beam
用那個一環一環的Beam來描述
Where is your action now?
這個你現在動作大概在哪裡
but something so complicated
但是這麼複雜的東西
It can be converted into a Feature Point
它可以轉換成一個Feature Point
Transfer to a spot in Chase Fund
調到Chase Fund 裡面一個點
so it's there
所以它在那裡
You can use a high Dimension thing
你就可以用一個高Dimension的東西
to describe its trajectory like this
去描述它的軌跡這樣
so you mean
所以您的意思是說
Each point is an action combination
每一個點是一個動作組合的
Description of dealing with seniors
對付學長的描述
not that word
並不是說那個詞字
deal with its background
跟它背景的對付
Yes
是的
It Features Bay
它的Features Bay
Can be a High Dimension Features Bay
可以是一個High Dimension的Features Bay
who is it
是誰啊
In fact, I just heard that there is a place that I am very concerned about
其實剛剛聽到現在有個地方很在意
that is
就是說
I trust you as a scholar
我相信你作為一個學者
what research are you going to do next
你下一步要做什麼研究
should be from a journal with which you are familiar
應該從你熟悉的期刊
Or the discussion of related scholars can understand
或是相關的學者的討論可以了解
But look inside your speech
但是看您的演講裡面
Many research directions seem to be very applied
很多的研究方向好像是很應用
and many of us
而且很多是我們
In fact, at least I didn't think of it
其實至少我沒有想到的
how do you get these ideas
請問你怎麼樣得到這些創意
to decide what problem you want to solve
去決定你要解決什麼問題
or from what do you think you can do
或是從你覺得你能夠做哪些問題
Thanks
謝謝
This is where my students spend the most time
這是我的學生花最多的時間
looking for a topic
在找題目
because when they are looking
因為他們在找的時候
to do this i would not
要做這個我會不要
do that i don't want
做那個我不要
I know what we're going to do
我知道我們要做什麼題目
Sometimes it's a topic I give them
有時候是我給他們的一個題目
i want to do this
我要做這個
it was like this in the early days
早期的時候是這樣
Because the early days were relatively young
因為早期的時候比較年輕
I think about many topics
就想很多題目
But because there are more students
但是因為學生比較多了以後
We spend this time talking about
我們花的這個時間是在講
Do you want to do this topic
要不要做這個題目
I usually ask him
我通常會問他說
What do you think you will contribute after finishing
你覺得做完以後有什麼貢獻
if not don't do it
如果沒有就不要做
Don't publish a paper because the future is not good
因為接下來不好也不要出paper
what happened to us a while ago
我們前陣子發生的事情
In fact, I don't deserve much
其實我配的不多
If I don't participate in many places, I won't be named
很多地方我如果不參與我就不掛名了
That's not much cooperation
那配合是不多的
Because I don't want to do something I don't understand
因為我不希望做一些我不懂的東西
or do something I don't even know
或做一些我根本就不知道的事情
We spend the most time looking for topics
我們花最多的時間在找題目
Because I think finding a topic
因為我認為找一個題目
Determine the height of your research
決定你這個研究的高度
you found the topic well
你的題目找得好
your height is good
你的高度好
and it's easier for you to do
而且你比較容易做
because of that topic
因為那個題目
Once you think clearly, it will be easy for you to do it
你想得清楚以後你做就很容易做
Because it is a field of Y-Open
因為它是一個Y-Open的一個領域
But if say you find a
但是如果說你找到一個
follow what others do
跟著別人做的話
you will work hard
你會很辛苦
because it takes a lot of effort
因為你要花很多力氣
Why review related things and compare them?
去審備相關的東西去比較去幹嘛
because you follow behind
因為你跟著人家後面
you have to do better than him
你必須要做得比他更好
Then if you do something new
那你如果做一些新的東西的時候
no one has done
沒有人做過
you did a great job
那你太好做了
you do whatever you want anyway
你隨便做一做反正
Everyone will think it is very good and fun.
大家會覺得很不錯很好玩這樣
What the teacher is going to say is to say
這位老師要說的是說
In fact, the teacher brainstorms broadly in a clear way
老師實際上是以明文集思廣義討論的方法
to find out the topic like this
去找出題目這樣
i will quiz them
我會考問他們的
Back off because that's what I do
知難而退,因為我自己就是這樣做的
It's not the same in the United States as in Taiwan
在美國跟台灣不太一樣
In fact, there are many teachers in the United States who let you do it yourself
在美國老師其實有很多讓你自己去做
But because of that environment, the environment doesn't matter
但是因為那個環境,大環境沒關係
Because all your colleagues are like this
因為你的同才都是這樣子
so you get used to it
所以你會很習慣這樣
Taiwan is different
台灣比較不一樣
Sometimes there are some students in Taiwan, you don’t need to mention them
台灣有時候有些學生你不需要提點他一下
The way to make a point is that this topic is not good, don't do it
提點方式就是這個題目不好,不要做
Maybe he didn't understand at the beginning
那是可能他一開始的時候不了解
But when what we publish later is highly consumed
可是當我們後來發表的東西被高度飲用的時候
He gradually understood why he did this
他就慢慢了解為什麼要這樣做
Many times we create a wave of elves to see
很多時候我們出一根波的精靈要看的
No one wants to post, no one wants to see your stuff
是沒有人要曬,沒有人要看你的東西
But when you do a lot of things and a lot of people are watching
可是當你做很多東西都很多人在看的時候
you give yourself a confidence
你給自己一個信心
Moreover, the research environment in Taiwan is relatively good
而且對整個台灣的研究環境也比較好
Because what we want to improve is our impact not our quantity
因為我們要提高的是我們的impact而不是我們的數量
Quantity doesn't matter
數量其實沒什麼用
Everyone, think about a question
各位想個問題
please
請
sorry
對不起
piece at digit point
在數位點的一塊
Saw some of your retouching
看到你在修圖的一些
you know
你有就了解
some outside some
一些外面的一些
Just some retouching
就是在修圖的一些
use some off-the-shelf toys
用一些現成的玩具
like photoshop
像 Photoshop
Fotain fact
Fotain fact
etc.
等等
because of you
因為你這個
developing this set
在發展這一套
is self-developed out of
是自己發展出於
Is it your own broken stick?
自己的破棍嗎
Or
還是說
is we play from that school
是我們從那校玩
Because if you say image processor
因為你如果說影像處理人
Image processing people rarely use Photoshop
影像處理人很少去用 Photoshop
Because your technique is definitely better than Photoshop
因為你技術絕對比 Photoshop好
That is to say, if you
就是說你如果
Fotoshop doesn't fit as it should
Fotoshop不因為它要適合
everyone can use
大家都能用
This thing we designed
我們設計的這一個東西
is to make the national archives available
是讓國家檔案取得
These people can go to repair our handmade
這些人能夠去修補我們手製
Very poor quality, just old videos and old photos
品質很差的,只是老影片跟老照片
So of course he is technically more advanced.
所以他技術上當然是比較高的
But almost you might turn around
但是差點你可能就變相轉
It becomes common to promote to everyone
變成推廣到大家是一般的
many need to collect
很多需要典藏的
Like Art Museum, Sister Gela, M2
像美術館、葛拉姐、M2
They also have a lot of collections
他們自己也有很多的典藏的
Then I hope that the party will do this.
那我是希望黨上局去做這個事情
Because we later put that
因為我們後來在把那個
Ridio in painting stuff turns it into software
Ridio in painting的東西把它變成軟體的
After the interface was completed, it took a year and a half
界面了以後,花的時間是一年半
In fact, it is also a harm to Dr. Tang.
其實對於唐博士來講也是一個傷害
Because that was actually
因為那個本來其實
It is best if you can do it with the salary of ability and performance
如果有能力成績的工資去做的話是最好的
Because we should spend our energy on the hardest part of the front end
因為我們應該把力氣花在前端最難的地方
Then there's the fact that we don't want to make money
再來就是我們也不想賺錢
I don't really want to make money, but I hope to do the most advanced things
不是很想賺錢,但是希望做最領先的東西
But someone was able to turn it into usable software
但是有人能夠把它變成可以用的軟體
that's our happiest
那是我們最高興的
please
請
Thank you professor for letting us see many things
謝謝教授讓我們看到很多東西
Because I recently bought a Godfather
因為我最近買了一個Godfather
Buray's full set of stuff
Buray的全套的東西
When there's a Bondest in there explaining how they're going to fix those
當裡面有個Bondest在介紹說他們如何去修復那些
This seems to be something similar
這個好像有點類似的東西
that's what fixes these
就是修復這些的
What's even better about them is that they return to their original color
他們更厲害是他們復原原來的顏色
Our program also has this function
我們這個Program也是有這樣功能
Or restore the original color
還是說復原原來的顏色
you mean color don't you
你是說彩色是不是
They were originally when Godfather was filming
他們本來Godfather在拍的時候
he has some parts of color
他有一些部分的顏色
because he is for him
因為他是以他為的
i change that hue
我改變那個色調
not our main purpose
不是我們最主要的目的
we didn't do that
我們並沒有做那個事情
because you've seen that ww2 recently
因為你最近有看到那個2次大戰
Actually, is the video in color?
其實影片彩色的有沒有
but it's done well
不過這做得很好
This is actually commissioned by the company.
這其實都是委託公司做的
it was originally black and white
它本來是黑白的
it does it just fine
它把它做的蠻好的
i watched a lot of documentaries
我看了很多紀錄片
Documentary of that war
那個戰爭的紀錄片
Since that part of the family has already done so well
那既然那個部分人家已經做得那麼好
that's not our focus
那也不是我們的focus
not a significant part of us
不是我們的重要部分
we want to mend
我們是希望去修補
is the broken part
就是已經壞掉的部分
so different
所以不太一樣
And the quality of our images is very poor
而且我們的image的quality都非常差
After Scan
Scan以後的
Good quadding and bad quality
好的quadding跟壞的quality
In fact, when doing
其實在做的時候
just now you saw that dog
剛剛你有看到那條狗
Because the dog is missing anyway, it's actually very simple
因為狗反正不見其實很簡單
Because the dog tone is too clear
因為狗色調太清楚了
easy to find
很容易發現
easy to handle
很容易處理
but the ladies
可是那些太太們
It's not easy
要不見不容易
because of the taste between its background
因為它的背景之間的口味
is big
是很大的
So its mouse position is very high
所以它的mouse的位置是很高的
so it's hard to get it off
所以要把它弄掉那是很難的
It's the insiders who know it when they see it.
就是內行的人一看到就知道
what does a master look like
高手是什麼樣子
because he knows what to say
因為他知道說我講什麼
Color is easy to get
彩色的很好弄
Because it's colored it has tint or something
因為彩色的它有色調什麼的
it's black and white and that
它是黑白的又是那種
when he was filming, when he was plasticizing
他在拍影片的時候,他塑化的時候
In fact, it introduces a lot of noise
其實就引進了很多雜訊
So when he handles, his beat will
所以他處理的時候,他的拍會
many issues to deal with
就很多問題要去處理
wait a minute there is still a problem
等一下,還有問題
Do you have any questions?
同學有沒有問題
what do we learn
我們學什麼
So now the archives office
所以現在那個檔案局的
The ones you plan to transfer to the Archives Bureau are still in the
你們計轉給檔案局的,還繼續在
no money, no money
那沒有錢,不要錢的
So we use the state
所以我們用國家
digital point length project
數位點長的計畫
so just do it well and leave it to them
所以就把它做好,就交給他們
do they have
他們有沒有
They were repairing it a while ago
他們前陣子在修復
Some old videos of Yilan County Government
宜蘭縣政府的一些老影片
old photo
老照片
they will have some
他們會有一些
Feedback questions
回饋的問題
Yes, that one seems to be okay
有,那個好像還好
seems to be ok
好像還好
is that cambers he will
就是那個坎伯斯他會
So it's good to compare with them
所以跟他們的對比還好
ask the professor
請教教授
Restorative photos of some techniques you just introduced
您剛介紹一些技術的修復質的照片
If it's like a painting at the Palais de la Rovere
如果像是羅福宮的畫作
those world cultures
那些世界文化
Is it possible to go through this way
是不是也可以經過這個樣
to fix
去修復
to allow him to save
去讓他能夠保存
Always be exactly the same as the original painting
永遠都跟原來的畫作完全一樣
if there is a defect
如果有瑕疵
If there is a flaw that means it is not well preserved
有就是說保存得不太好的瑕疵的話
Is there a way to go through this
是不是要辦法經過這樣
here's the fix
這裡的修復
In fact, this sentence may
其實這句話可能
I said that the two words of repairing are not precise enough.
我講修復這兩個字不夠精準
In fact, because I changed it to
其實因為就把它改成
blind your eyes
讓你眼睛看不出來
have flaws
有瑕疵
just start talking like this
就開始這樣講
Because it is a digital thing
因為它是數碩化的東西
where he was originally flawed
那他原來有瑕疵的地方
I use image processing method
我用影像處理的方法
fooled your eyes
騙過你的眼睛
so that you don't know that there is a flaw in that place
讓你不知道那個地方有瑕疵
in this way
這樣子
you just introduced that technique
你剛剛介紹那種技術
Is it ever used in
是不是曾經用在
that world manga
那個世界的漫畫上
no no no
沒有沒有沒有
will it let us touch
它會不會讓我們碰
We used to be able to let Menah Lusha
我們曾經可以讓門阿綠沙
smile bigger
笑得更大
will it be brighter
會不會更燦爛
will it be easier
會不會比較簡單
Then he smiles brighter
那他笑得更燦爛
what will happen
會怎麼樣
Thank you, teacher
謝謝老師
In fact, I am most grateful to the teacher
其實我最謝謝老師
are the last two birth control
是最後兩個節育
because
因為
technology is technology
科技是科技
Technology is still a cold thing
科技還是很冷的東西
of course
當然是說
Because I think everyone who has a Ph.D.
因為我想每一個念過博士的
Or in terms of senior intellectuals
或者是說在高級知識分子這一塊
or in pursuit of domestic
或者是在追求國內
impact factor this piece
impact factor這一塊
in this speech today
今天在這個演講裡面
I miss knowledge
說實在知識想念
but i think
可是我覺得
is in this student's
是在這個學生的
concern for humanity
對人文的關懷
care for society
對社會的關懷
that kind of warmth
那種溫暖
And the last epilogue is for all the scientists present
然後最後這個結語是送給所有在座科學人
Learning is the same
學問也是一樣
The same goes for learning
做學問也是一樣
I have done twenty or thirty years of research
我是做了二三十年的研究
Then my father passed away more than two years ago
然後父親兩年多以前過世
I spent more time with my mother after she passed away
過世以後我花比較多時間陪我母親
we're pissed off
我們已經發了氣碎
I told you earlier
我之前跟各位講一下
In fact, I have been so many years
其實我這麼多年來
I later found out one thing
我後來發現一件事情
I was younger when I was younger
年輕的時候我比較年輕氣盛
but i later found out
可是我後來發現
Thieves won't suffer
後盜是不會吃虧的
I won't suffer if I steal later
後盜的我也是不會吃虧的
be kind
帶人和善
be kind to others
能夠善待別人
Those who steal later will never suffer
後盜的人是絕對不會吃虧的
because you won't bother
因為你的麻煩都不會
there will be a noisy trouble
人家會有一個吵麻煩
People will PASS you
人家會擺PASS你
because he won't think of you
因為他不會想到你
because we have to call me Frankenstein
因為我們有叫我科學怪人
It was when I was young that I used to wake up in the middle of the night
就是我年輕的時候常常半夜就
suddenly in the middle of the night
半夜就突然間
All of a sudden, I ran until it was dawn and came back
突然間就跑到時間是天亮再回來
Then slip wind I often disappear
然後滑風我就常常不見了
But then I got older
但是後來年紀大了
Physical strength is also relatively poor
體力也比較不好
But because of such a preference
但是因為這樣的一個喜好
make animals
做動物
That's how you like it, so you can avoid many disasters
就是這樣喜好,讓你避掉很多禍
Anyway, I don't have anything to say
反正我沒有什麼好站牙平意
Anyway, you do what I should do
反正你做我自己該做的事情
do it fast, for a piece of sky
做得很快的,為了一片天
Then there is a costume in my lab
那我這實驗室裡面擺了一個服裝
It's not a costume, it's a costume
不是服裝,就是一個服裝
The person who is convinced, the most convinced person is the most convinced person
有服氣的人,最有服氣的人就是後到人最有服氣
I want students to understand this
我希望學生都能夠了解這一點
not only knowledge
不是只有學問
If you want to step on other people's shoulders
如果要踩著別人肩膀上去的話
that knowledge is false
那個學問是假的
That is not true
那不是真的
your knowledge is painted on the worst
你的學問是畫在最壞事上面
If so, that's not real knowledge.
那這樣的話那不是真的學問
The real strength should be drawn on the high mouth
真的力氣應該畫在高口上
draw on difficult problems
畫在難的問題上面
That way you can make the best things
這樣的話你才有辦法做出最好的東西
please also
還請
If it is in the general aspect of art
如果是在藝術普分面
They are generally in the most color and texture life
他們一般在最顏色還有質感生命
relatively high requirements
要求的比較高
In this part we are planning
在這一部分我們在做計畫
is the part that compares digits now
是現在比較數位的部分
Are there any humanities in this distance?
那有沒有在這個跨遠的那些人文
It's like dividing those
就好像普分那些
Tommy some experts to learn
湯麗一些專家去學習
we no longer have
我們現在已經沒有
all the singing is over
所有的演唱已經結束了
Now just do the follow-up Maintain
現在只是做後續的Maintain
is to keep
就是持續保存
keep the original team
保持原來的團隊
But it's not already out of technology research and development
但是它不是已經不是技術研發的
Then the question you just mentioned is about a
那你剛剛講的那個問題是在講一個
quality is the part of aesthetics
quality 就是美學那個部分
Now it becomes a multimedia
現在它變成一個在多媒體
A notable part of the study
研究裡面的一個顯學
we won't talk about quality anymore
我們不會再講quality
So they quantice this quality
所以他們quantice這個quality
It is aesthetics that quantifies it
就是美學它把它量化
So they can use a standard
所以他們可以用一個標準
to some standards
對一些標準來看說
Isn't this thing beautiful?
這個東西是不是美是不是好這樣子
Of course I don't agree
當然我不是很認同
I think that's a bit lacking
我覺得那個有點欠缺
because everyone to everyone
因為每個人對每個人
Everyone's opinion is different
每個人的那個看法是不一樣的
just look at a girl
光看一個女孩子
You don't necessarily think he's pretty.
你覺得他漂亮漂亮就不一定
Although my wife is not very good looking
雖然我太太就長得不怎麼樣
But I think when my wife is sixty
可是我認為我太太六十歲的時候
He still has a good temperament
他還是很有氣質還是很好
that he won't change
就是他不會改變
He is about the same age as 20 and 60
他二十歲跟六十歲是差不多的
But from a general aesthetic point of view
但是以一般美學的觀點
From the point of view of most people's aesthetics
大部分人的美學的觀點來看的話
he is not beautiful
他是不美的
He can only be called my friend
他只能稱為我朋友講的
Caller
叫手交代者
but
但是
But when people live to be fifty or sixty years old, sixty or seventy years old
但是人活到五六十歲六七十歲的時候
are old, right?
都老了對不對
no more ugly
再沒也變醜了
But the most important thing is this
但其實最重要的就是這個東西
What's in your head is more important
你腦袋裡面的東西比較重要
at that time
那時候
sorry
對不起
i didn't answer you
我沒有回答你
That aesthetic is now being practiced by many people
那個美學現在有很多人在做
yes indeed
是的確
but i didn't do that
但是我沒有做那一塊
I compare that
我比較那個
more positive
比較正一點
ok i have what to bring to answer the question
好,我有帶什麼解答問題
come please
來,請
I think it's a follow-up question, please continue
我想算是接著問,請教下去
That is to say, as the teacher just showed a technique is considered
就是說,像老師剛剛有展示一個技術是算
The number of people in the video can be automatically added to a large number
影片裡面的人數,然後可以自動的大量的
To see this matter, in other words, he can automatically
去看這件事情,換言之就是他可以自動的
Watch a lot of videos and say how many people are there
對一大堆影片注視說這裡面人數有多少
One question that comes to mind in this way is, are we right
這樣子我想到的一個問題就是,那是否我們對
When you want to know a certain aspect of information when you want to know a certain aspect of information
數位點長資料,想要了解某個方面的資訊的時候
You have to think of another set of algorithms to be able to handle it.
都要再想一套演算法才能夠處理得出來
Is there an algorithm that takes a
有沒有一個演算法可以把一個
Or a lot of data with long digits, those
或是說一大堆的數位點長資料,那一些
In other words, it is equivalent to saying that it can be described in a relatively complete way.
也就是說等於說可以比較完整的把它描述完畢,不需要
If I want to know the number of people, I have to trouble the teacher for ten years. Then I want to know the next day.
我想知道人數就要麻煩老師做了十年,那第二天想要了解
where are these
這些是在哪些地方
I'm going to be busy doing two things
就要忙忙做兩個樣子
yes i tell you
對,我跟你講
to you...
對,你...
I actually... you take a closer look at what we've done
我其實...你仔細看一下我們所做的問題
In fact, it's all about engineering
其實都是engineering的問題
But the problem of engineering does not mean that there will be no size in the middle
但是做engineering的問題不代表它中間不會有size
what we can do
那我們能夠做的
Because I've come this far
因為我已經走到這一行了
I know what I'm doing is an engineering problem
我知道我做的是一個engineering的問題
is not a perfect field
是不太完美的領域
but i can only try
但是我只能盡量
for the survival of the students
因為為了學生的生存
For the future of students
為了學生以後的出路
I have to be in the middle of the process of this project
我必須在這個工程的過程中間
find a size
找出一個size
Let them learn some valuable things from the middle
讓他們能夠從中間學到一些比較可貴的東西
instead of black hands
而不是用黑手
Just use the Taoist calendar
就是用道歷法
To solve the problem with engineering methods
去把問題用工程的方法去把它解決
You solve the problem though
你雖然解決的問題
But it is 0 in learning
但是在學習上面是0
So we'll try to think of some
所以我們會試圖去想一些
During this process
在這個過程中
Think of something scientific to infuse it
想一些科學的東西把它注入
Raise the bar for this question
讓這個問題的門檻也變高
Because engineering problems you can use engineering methods to solve
因為工程的問題你可以用工程方法去解決
But in the middle, if you can use the scientific method to enter
但是中間如果可以用科學的方法進來的時候
its bar will get higher
它的門檻會變高
It becomes higher when approaching two thresholds
接近兩個門檻就變高
So I didn't count the things that were transferred out
所以我沒有計轉出去的東西
when i do it with this attitude
我用這樣的態度去做的時候
there is a vendor
有一個廠商
He can't be called a master's or a doctor's manager
他不可能叫一個碩士或一個博士的經理
Bring a few masters to do it
帶了幾個碩士做得到
he can't do it
他做不到的
because the bar is high
因為那個門檻是很高的
because he has something scientific
因為他有科學的東西
There is Science in it
有Science在裡面
That product is also relatively hidden.
那那個產品也是比較隱蔽的
Just like our current Largan
就像我們現在的大立光一樣
The reason why Largan makes so much money
大立光之所以會賺這麼多錢
Only the first one he stayed in Taiwan
只有第一個他留在台灣
The second one he used plastic instead of glass
第二個他用塑膠取代玻璃
his cost is very low
他的成本很低
His technique is good
他的技術又好
So his world power is 50%
所以他的世界的戰力是50%
Half of the lens is his whole world
鏡頭有一半是他的全世界
so he can be so good
所以他可以這麼好
Then you'll know that Mitch
那你會知道說那個Mitch
his science stuff is there
他的科學的東西在那裡
so he can
所以他可以
was he originally a doctor
他本來是醫生嘛
this son took
這個兒子接了
his father gave him
他爸爸交給他
this son is a doctor
這個兒子是醫生
But he just jumped in and made Largan shots
但是他就跳進去做大立光的鏡頭
well-done
做得很好
the same reason
同樣的道理
He's supposed to do science stuff as well
他應該做科學的東西也是這樣
You do it on that joint for mental strength
你為了心力去在那個關節點上做
When doing science
把科學做進去的時候
Your process is very valuable
你這個過程就是很可貴的
Why? Because it is not easy for others to surpass you
為什麼?因為別人不容易輕易的能夠超越你
so for students
這樣對學生來講
To everyone who works with you
對所有跟你一起工作的人來講
one of the best training
一個最好的訓練
because they are in a difficult
因為他們在一個很困難
like that diamond
就像那個鑽石一樣
you are more stressed
你壓力大一點
Are you a diamond again?
你又是鑽石嗎?
you stress less
你壓力少一點
become soil without pressure
就沒有壓力就變土壤
Excuse me
不好意思
professor again
教授再請教你一下
if that old photo
如果說那個老照片
What about inventions like the one you just mentioned?
有像剛剛你講的發明都怎麼樣
Is there any software on the market that can fix it?
現在市面上有這樣軟體可以修復嗎?
actually don't know
其實不太知道
I know it's possible to have software
我知道有可能有軟體
But I didn't actually look for those software
但是我其實沒有去找那些軟體
that maybe
那也許有
Because the technical threshold is not very high
因為那個技術門檻也不是很高
VDL is more difficult
VDL比較困難
But Yiyiju
但是依依舉
Just saw that M-POP
剛有看到那個M-POP
that we have given one to the archives office
那個我們有給那個檔案局一個
That's what he did
那其實他是做
He needs an Aged Detection
他是要有一個Aged Detection
to catch Crees
去抓到Crees
It's Crees stuff
就是Crees的這些東西
That Crees sometimes you catch
那個Crees有時候你會抓到
Because many things and clothes also have Crees
因為很多東西衣服也有Crees
also have boundaries
也有邊界
so leave a space
那所以留一個空間
let these to study these
讓這些要修讀的這些
ladies and gentlemen
先生小姐們
he doesn't know computer
他不懂電腦
He doesn't have a Mouse
他沒有一個Mouse
to tick which are places
去勾哪些是地方
is required
是需要修讀的
After ticking
勾好以後
The system will automatically
這系統自動會把他
kill him where it should be done
該做的地方就把他做掉
he is borrowing
他才是借用
What was carried off did him away
扛掉的東西把他做掉
ask you that again
再請教你那個
say in the computer
就說在電腦裡面
the one of us
那我們那個人
there will be an editor or something
會有一個編輯什麼的
then you go in and edit
那你進去編輯
like just now you made that picture light up
像剛剛你讓那個照片亮出來
then we are on the computer
那我們在電腦上
After that and that light up
那個那個亮出來之後
there is no way like
就沒有辦法像
the thing we just showed
我們剛剛顯示出來的那個東西
we missed it
我們就誤掉了
Yes, that, that, actually that
對對那個那個其實那個
too big a miss
太大一個誤掉
just one
只是一個
a Presentation
一個Presentation
that method
那個手法而已
He is actually the end result
他其實就是最後的結果
He just puts it out with the middle process
他只要用中間的過程把它放出來
That's not what I did
那那個不是我做的
That's my Postart
那個是我的那個Postart
bomb plus that bomb mode
彈加那種彈模式
That Xiao Fenyu
那個蕭芬妤
Mr. Xiao is here
蕭先生他在
Universal Washington Seattle
Universal Washington Seattle
he did
他做的
He is slowly showing it
他是把它慢慢呈現出來
So the result he just had
所以他剛剛那個結果
In the results report of the National Science Council
在國科會的成果報告裡面
there was a press conference
有一次記者會
I think we'll be clear
我覺得我們就會很清楚的
Then we use that editor's
那我們用那個編輯的
because what to do
因為去做的話怎麼做
yes that's just a
對 那個只是一個
Presentation is just a method
Presentation的一個手法而已
right
對
Okay, thank you
好 謝謝
brightness brightness change
亮度 亮度改變
He actually does repair work
他其實有做修復的工作
yes i just need a little bit out
對 我只需要一點點出
Yes I have people involved in a lot of restoration
對 我有參與很多修復的人
any left
還有沒有
I'm not like him
我比他不是這樣
I am very very thankful today
我今天非常非常感謝
drug researcher
藥研究員
I think I should add
我覺得我要補充一點
is what he just presented
就是他剛剛呈現的
he has many conclusions
他有很多很多結論
there is one more important thing
還有一個很重要的東西
It can be heard from his speech
可以聽得出來從他的演講裡面
I could tell he was very, very interested
聽得出來他非常非常有興趣
all the things he does
他做的所有的東西
所以 everything is worth it
所以 everything is worth it
ok thank you all for today
好 今天謝謝大家
then i now
然後我現在
we are very grateful once to you
我們非常感謝一旦給你
Thanks
謝謝